Academia Sinica's 2023 Governor's Vision
中央研究院の2023年知事ビジョン
Dean Wang Shijie's popular science lecture begins
王世傑学部長の人気科学講義が始まる
We have asked Vice President Huang Jingxin to host for us
黄景新副大統領に司会をお願いしました。
The 132nd birthday of President Wang Shijie Gu
王世傑九総統生誕 132 周年
In order to express our memory and respect for President Wang
王総統への追悼と敬意を表するため
At this time of year
この時期には
commemorative lectures will be held
記念講演会が開催されます
President Wang Shijie is the fourth president of the hospital
王世傑院長は同病院の4代目院長となる
During his term of office, he made every effort to promote academic cooperation between China and the United States
任期中、彼は中国と米国の学術協力の促進に全力を尽くした。
Yannan Overseas Outstanding Scholars Return to Taiwan to Give Lectures
延南海外の優秀な学者が台湾に戻って講演
Qiu Jianzhong's Center for American Studies
邱建中のアメリカ研究センター
Institute of Europe and America
欧米研究所
It is also the service unit of Wang Fu Research Institute
王府研究所のサービス部門でもあります
This establishment has been established for more than 50 years
創業50年以上の老舗です
It also hosts the Economic Research Institute
経済研究所も主催している
Institute of Restoration Physics, etc.
修復物理研究所など
For the cultivation of national talents and the improvement of science and technology, the influence is self-fulfilling
国民人材の育成と科学技術の向上のため、影響力は自己実現的である
tonight's keynote speaker
今夜の基調講演者
Associate Researcher Wang Zhiming of the Institute of European and American Studies
欧米研究所 准研究員 王志銘
He graduated from the Department of Foreign Languages, National Tsing Hua University
国立清華大学外国語学部卒業
M.A. in Comparative Literature from National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学比較文学修士号取得
Care about University of California, Santa Claus
カリフォルニア大学サンタクロースを気遣う
Ph.D.
博士号
Now it is the European and American Institute of our hospital
現在は当院の欧米研究所となっております
Institute of Social Culture, Yangming Jiaotong University
陽明交通大学社会文化研究所
He hired each other as professors
彼はお互いを教授として雇った
He is elected from 2021 to 2022
彼は2021年から2022年まで選出される
Visiting scholar of China Experience Society
中国体験協会客員研究員
it's an honor
それは光栄です
Once in 2017 to 2018
2017年から2018年に1回
single segment
単一セグメント
Visiting scholar of China Academy of Art
中国芸術院客員研究員
Researcher Wang Fu mainly studies Lin Wei
研究者ワン・フーは主にリン・ウェイを研究しています
Asian American Literature
アジア系アメリカ人文学
Colonial Theory after Agenda Cultural Studies
アジェンダ文化研究後の植民地理論
recent interest
最近の興味
Turning to Jiangjie Geopolitics
江街地政学に目を向ける
as a refugee
難民として
His writings are very rich
彼の著作は非常に豊かです
its tyranny
その圧制
Landed in foreign language studies in Taiwan
台湾に語学留学に上陸
Centennial trajectory
百年軌跡
Take the Foreign Languages ​​Department of National Taiwan University as an example
国立台湾大学外国語学部を例に挙げます。
Exploring the Cold War
冷戦を探る
Native European and American Literature
ヨーロッパとアメリカのネイティブ文学
Curriculum Planning and the Political Operations in It
カリキュラム計画とその中の政治的運営
In last year 2022
昨年2022年に
Humanities and Social Sciences
人文社会科学
academic book chief
学術書主任
it's very competitive
とても競争力がある
also national
国民的でもある
No wonder I look familiar to you
私があなたに見覚えがあるのも不思議ではありません
Because I'm giving this award
この賞をあげるからには
last year
去年
He suddenly won the Academy's Humanities and Social Sciences Exclusive Award
彼は突然アカデミーの人文社会科学特別賞を受賞した
This year
今年
There are universal gains in March
3月にはユニバーサルゲインがあります
National Science and Health Outstanding Research Award
国家科学と健康優秀研究賞
also became 2014
2014年にもなりました
Won the Academy Young Writer Award
アカデミー若手作家賞を受賞
2009 National Science Guard Wu Dayou Memorial Award
2009年国家科学警備隊呉大佑記念賞
You have won all the awards in Taiwan
台湾ですべての賞を受賞しました
and the 2008 American Studies Association
および2008年アメリカ研究協会
Shenyan Chubby International Scholars Paper Award
瀋陽ぽっちゃり国際学者論文賞
what is his english
彼の英語は何ですか
What country is he Japanese from?
彼はどこの国から来た日本人ですか?
He is an outstanding and very young humanist scholar
彼はとても優秀で若い人文主義の学者です
I won't say more
これ以上は言いません
Please give us a round of applause to welcome Wang Huyan to the rescue
王滬燕の救助を歓迎するために拍手をお願いします
Tell the story of this refugee
この難民の話をしてください
Power Freedom and Dignity Keynote Speeches
権力の自由と尊厳の基調講演
Presumably exciting
おそらくエキサイティングな
Then we sit together and listen
それから私たちは一緒に座って聞きます
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
Family members of Vice President Hua and then former President Wang Shijie
華副総統と王世傑元総統の家族
And hello to all the audience friends here
そしてここにいる視聴者の友人の皆さん、こんにちは。
Thank you so much friends for coming tonight
今夜来てくれた友達、本当にありがとう
I'm sorry, it's reversed
ごめんなさい、逆になってしまいました
Come to this occasion to hear this speech
このスピーチを聞くためにこの機会に来ました
That
それか
Chen Rugang, Vice President Wang, talked about this period of time
陳如剛氏、王副総統はこの時期について語った。
I saw him quite a lot
私は彼をよく見ました
So I can recognize it if I want to
だから、その気になれば認識できるよ
special thanks to him
彼に特別な感謝を
because during this time
この間だから
including from to
からからまでを含む
At the beginning of this visit, there are actually a lot of troubles to Vice President Huang's place.
今回の訪問当初、黄副総統のところには実際に多くの問題があった。
Then let Vice President Huang be the host and introduce today
それでは、黄副社長に司会を務めていただき、今日の紹介をさせていただきます
For me, it is actually a very, very great honor
私にとって、それは実際、とてもとても光栄なことです
Especially on such an occasion today is the commemorative lecture given by former President Wang Shijie
特に今日はこのような機会に、王世傑元総統の記念講演が行われました。
As Vice President Wang mentioned just now, it means that Europe and the United States are actually in the
先ほど王副主席がおっしゃったように、ヨーロッパとアメリカが実際に参加しているということです。
President Wang promoted the establishment of
王総統は設立を推進した。
And he is very concerned. In fact, this morning he even read some of the techniques in his diary.
実際、今朝、彼は自分の日記に書かれているテクニックの一部を読みました。
It can be seen that during the period from 1968 to 1969, he was constantly promoting and facilitating the establishment of such a new unit
1968 年から 1969 年にかけて、彼は常にそのような新しい部隊の設立を推進し、促進していたことがわかります。
So for me to be the host of this lecture today
今日私がこの講演会の司会を務めることになりました
It's a great honor and a lot of pressure
大変光栄なことですが、大変なプレッシャーでもあります
never thought to say
言うことを考えたこともなかった
In fact, I have given so many speeches today, I feel that the special pressure is a little bit greater.
実際、今日はたくさんのスピーチをさせていただきましたので、特別なプレッシャーが少し大きくなったと感じています。
But today's speech has a big purpose, in fact, the research institute faces the public
しかし、今日の講演には大きな目的があり、実は研究所は国民に向けて
To make some such an attempt on the popularization of humanities
人文科学の普及にそのような試みをする
Then this also means that apart from doing its own research in the depths of Xiangyata, the research institute
そうすると、これはまた、研究機関が香耶塔の深部で独自の研究を行うこととは別に、
In fact, we also hope that our research can bring some inspiration to the public and point to some different concerns.
実際、私たちはまた、私たちの研究が一般の人々に何らかのインスピレーションをもたらし、いくつかの異なる懸念を指摘できることを願っています。
Mr. Lin, who was here just now, reminded me that many friends may also be very concerned about this issue of refugees.
先ほどここに来ていたリンさんは、多くの友人もこの難民問題について非常に懸念しているかもしれないと私に思い出させてくれました。
I am curious if the refugee issue I am talking about today is related to the practice of saving refugees in the real world
今日私が話している難民問題が、現実世界での難民救済活動と関連しているかどうか知りたいです。
Of course there are some details that are close, but there are also some big differences.
もちろん、細部では近い部分もありますが、大きな違いもいくつかあります。
Then what I want to say is actually in the context of humanities science popularization
では、私が言いたいのは、実は人文科学普及の文脈でのことです。
What I want to bring to you today is not so much about the experience of the refugees themselves
今日私が皆さんにお届けしたいのは、難民自身の経験についてではありません。
more is to want through literature
文学を通じてより多くのことを望むこと
Learned such a perspective and media
そんな視点やメディアを学びました
how to discuss the story itself
ストーリー自体について議論する方法
Shaping Refugees
難民の形成
And what about the refugees themselves
そして難民自身はどうなるのか
stories about themselves
自分たちについての話
then why talk about refugees
ではなぜ難民について話すのか
Why talk about refugees at this time
なぜこの時期に難民の話をするのか
Why put refugee stories in
なぜ難民の話を入れるのか
In today's historical time and space in Taiwan
台湾の歴史的な時間と空間の中で
Let's talk about this now
今からこれについて話しましょう
I think
私が思うに
I believe many, many friends
私はたくさんの友達を信じています
should feel
感じるべきだ
for me
私のため
Discussion and development of this topic
このトピックの議論と発展
actually in
実際に
during my own research
私自身の研究中に
by reading in Yayi
ヤイ語で読むと
these writers who grew up in america
アメリカで育ったこれらの作家
They write their own
彼らは自分で書いています
so-called discrete experience
いわゆる離散的な経験
especially vietnamese writers
特にベトナムの作家
Talk about how they escaped from Vietnam
彼らがどのようにしてベトナムから脱出したかについて話す
came to america such a story
アメリカに来た、そんな話
And at the beginning I felt something about him
そして最初、私は彼について何かを感じました
interest and concern
興味と関心
then it's a bigger trigger
それならもっと大きなきっかけになる
Actually two years ago
実は2年前
In other words, it was two years ago and three years ago in 2020
つまり2年前と3年前の2020年です。
That is, the United States will withdraw its troops from Afghanistan in August 2020
つまり、米国は2020年8月にアフガニスタンから軍隊を撤退させることになる。
I don't know if you guys still remember the scene of the withdrawal
撤退のシーンをまだ覚えているかどうかはわかりませんが、
The helicopter took off from that platform
ヘリコプターはそのプラットフォームから離陸しました
Then there are the many Afghan people everywhere
そしてどこにでもたくさんのアフガニスタン人がいる
or can't get into the airport
もしくは空港に入れない
or can only wave on the platform
またはプラットフォーム上でのみ手を振ることができます
Or hope to catch the last class to leave Afghanistan
あるいは、アフガニスタンを離れる最後の授業に参加したいと思っています
So today in 2023
ということで、2023年の今日
Taiwan is also facing the threat of war in a certain sense
台湾もある意味戦争の脅威にさらされている
Even when I accompanied Boxi to Taiwan last year
去年ボクシーと一緒に台湾に行った時も
I even have a very apt feeling that
私は非常によくある感覚さえ持っています
in case something happens
何かが起こった場合に備えて
Will we become refugees too?
私たちも難民になってしまうのでしょうか？
In this sense
この意味で
Just from such an experience
まさにそんな経験から
Makes me think about the refugee problem
難民問題について考えさせられる
May not be those others who are waiting to be rescued in the distance
遠くで救助を待っている人たちではないかもしれない
It's right next to us and maybe even ourselves
それは私たちのすぐ隣、そしておそらく私たち自身さえも
own history and process
自分自身の歴史とプロセス
But let's hope it doesn't become our future
でもそれが私たちの未来にならないことを祈りましょう
That's why I feel that from this time on
だから今回からはそう感じます
Concerns over refugee issues
難民問題への懸念
Perhaps it is at this time that Taiwan society
おそらくこの時期、台湾社会は
a reminder that might be important
重要かもしれないリマインダー
So let's talk a little bit more about this topic
それでは、このトピックについてもう少し詳しく話しましょう
refugee story
難民の話
Of course the main character is a refugee
もちろん主人公は難民です
But at this angle of my entry
しかし、私のエントリーのこの角度では
more important may be the story itself
もっと重要なのはストーリーそのものかもしれない
Then I'll put this part of the story back later
それでは、その話の部分を後で戻します
Let me explain to you
説明させてください
Then in the subtitle
それからサブタイトルでは
power liberty and dignity
権力の自由と尊厳
In fact, several issues surrounding refugees
実際、難民を取り巻くいくつかの問題
related concepts
関連する概念
For example, why do you want to become a refugee?
たとえば、なぜ難民になりたいのですか？
why be a refugee
なぜ難民になるのか
because of lack of freedom
自由がないため
or hope for freedom
あるいは自由への希望
Why refugees deserve our attention
なぜ難民は私たちの注目に値するのか
because they are also subjects of power
彼らも権力の主体だから
or worthy of our considerable power
または私たちの大きな力に値する
even the existence of refugees
難民の存在さえも
He needs more than freedom and power
彼には自由と権力以上のものが必要だ
more
もっと
may be dignity
尊厳かもしれない
those different levels
それらの異なるレベル
Maybe it can help us to build a
おそらくそれは私たちが構築するのに役立つかもしれません
our one for refugees
難民のための私たちのもの
A more three-dimensional understanding
より立体的な理解
So let me start today's talk
それでは今日の話を始めましょう
I start with the W.H.O.D.N.
まずはW.H.O.D.Nから始めます。
This is a poet in England at the beginning of the patriotic century
これは愛国世紀初頭のイギリスの詩人です
is also a very famous modernist poet
非常に有名なモダニズムの詩人でもあります
Have traveled to China
中国に旅行したことがある
And then there are some interesting ones like these
そして、このような興味深いものがいくつかあります
what is this called
これは何と呼ばれていますか
poet's love relationship
詩人の恋愛関係
But love relationships I'm not here today
でも愛の関係 今日はここにいない
Simply put, in the 1930s
簡単に言うと1930年代
He actually paid attention to this
彼は実際にこれに注目しました
The so-called German
いわゆるドイツ人
these jewish refugees from central europe
中央ヨーロッパから来たこれらのユダヤ人難民
Then I wrote such a poem
それからこんな詩を書きました
I simply translate a little bit
ちょっとだけ翻訳してみます
He said there are tens of millions of souls in this city
彼はこの街には何千万もの魂がいると言った
but also live in these
しかし、これらにも住んでいます
But some people live in mansion villas
でもマンション別荘に住んでる人もいるよ
some people live in mansions
豪邸に住んでいる人もいる
live in a hole
穴の中に住んでいる
Then what
じゃあ何
for us
わたしたちのため
In fact, we are the group of people who have no place to live.
実際、私たちは住む場所がない人々の集団です。
And we're the ones who don't have a place to live
そして、住む場所がないのは私たちです
that once we had a country
かつて私たちには国があったということ
And we also used to think it was beautiful
そして私たちもそれが美しいと思っていました
But look at this map right now
でも今この地図を見てください
you can also find where it is
それがどこにあるかを見つけることもできます
but we can't go there
でも私たちはそこには行けません
honey we can't go there
ハニー、私たちはそこには行けません
On the grave in this village
この村の墓の上に
An old red mountain tree like this grows
こんな赤い山の古木が生えている
every spring
毎年春
it will re-germinate and re-grow
再び発芽して再び成長します
But what about our old passports?
しかし、古いパスポートはどうなるのでしょうか？
won't regrow
再生しません
Our old passports don't grow back
私たちの古いパスポートは元には戻らない
These officials of this half times
このハーフタイムの関係者たちは
knock and talk tell us
ノックして話してください
if you don't have a passport
パスポートを持っていない場合
Then you are speaking from an official point of view
そうするとあなたは公式の観点から話しているんですね
you no longer exist
あなたはもう存在しません
but we're still here baby
でも私たちはまだここにいるよ、ベイビー
but we're still here
でも私たちはまだここにいる
Then this is his care and concern for the Jewish refugees at that time
これは当時のユダヤ人難民に対する彼の配慮と気遣いです
Then let us also see
それでは、私たちも見てみましょう
refugee to refugee
難民から難民へ
In terms of description, there are actually a lot of layers
説明の面では、実際には多くのレイヤーがあります
A big part of it is actually his lack of power.
その大きな部分は実際には彼の力の欠如です。
or a view of the dispossessed state
または剥奪された状態の眺め
Well, this is also the most basic thing we usually do for refugees.
これは、私たちが難民に対して通常行っている最も基本的なことでもあります。
know
認識
But the most interesting thing I think is in this kind of strength
しかし、私が最も興味深いと思うのは、この種の強さです
He especially emphasized the matter of passports
彼は特にパスポートの問題を強調した
These refugees are not without passports
これらの難民はパスポートを持っていないわけではない
It's that his old passport is no longer valid
彼の古いパスポートはもう有効ではないということです
And when you don't have a passport
そして、パスポートを持っていないときは、
you no longer exist
あなたはもう存在しません
So what is this reaction
それでこの反応は何ですか
This reflects the fact that we are
これは私たちがこうであるという事実を反映しています。
This social life is actually in a very realistic sense
この社会生活は実際には非常に現実的な意味で
we live in this society
私たちはこの社会に生きています
Sometimes our credit cards and our ID cards are more important than our people
場合によっては、クレジット カードや ID カードが従業員よりも重要になることがあります
There was once such an example in the United States
かつてアメリカでもそんな例があった
one famous on the one hand at harvard
一方ではハーバード大学で有名な人物
Not a professor in America a black professor
アメリカの教授ではない、黒人の教授だ
Because of this, I can't get his ID on me at the moment.
このため、現時点では彼のIDを取得することができません。
by his this
彼のこれによって
It was the administrator of the residence who blocked the door.
ドアを封鎖したのは邸宅の管理人だった。
It's ironic that the admin doesn't recognize his face
管理人が彼の顔を認識していないのは皮肉です
I only recognize the ID he has on him.
私が認識しているのは彼が持っている ID だけです。
So for refugees
だから難民にとっては
Do not have a certificate or a legal certificate
証明書または法的証明書をお持ちでない場合
how to make him
彼をどうやって作るか
Documents that allow him to move
彼の移動を許可する書類
become part of the whole refugee story
難民の物語全体の一部になる
a very core key
非常にコアな鍵
Although in our daily life
私たちの日常生活の中でも
may be a trivial thing
些細なことかもしれない
If you don't have any documents, just go ahead and do it again.
書類がない場合は、もう一度やり直してください。
But when war comes
しかし、戦争が来ると
Documents may be the only thing that can prove you
書類があなたを証明できる唯一のものかもしれません
a material that still exists
まだ存在する素材
Then further I want to use such a
それからさらにそのようなものを使用したい
simple expansion
単純な拡張
Let's think about our past few years
ここ数年のことを考えてみましょう
In the past three to five years
ここ3～5年くらいで
In fact, refugees are the international
実際、難民は国際的な存在です
a huge huge issue
大きな大きな問題
You can see these photos
これらの写真を見ることができます
In fact, I deliberately unselected
実は意図的に選択を外しました
as several
いくつかとして
several perspectives to understand
理解するためのいくつかの視点
so-called refugee status
いわゆる難民状態
One perspective is of course the most famous one in the lower left corner
もちろん、左下隅にある最も有名な視点が 1 つあります。
Fleeing from Syria
シリアからの逃亡
on this beach in greece
ギリシャのこのビーチで
This little sea that fell dead over there
あそこで死んでしまったこの小さな海
Then also because of this photo
それからまたこの写真のせいで
Syria's Refugee Crisis
シリアの難民危機
Gaining great attention in the European Union
欧州連合で大きな注目を集めている
It also makes this Greece slowly unfold
それはまた、このギリシャをゆっくりと展開させます
including the refugee camp
難民キャンプも含めて
Then more such an action of humanitarian relief
それからさらにそのような人道的救援活動
This picture in the lower right corner
この写真の右下隅にあります
what we can see is
私たちが見ることができるのは
It turned out to be changed
変わっていることが判明した
We can see that it's actually a boat
それが実際に船であることがわかります
And it's a boat full of people
そしてそれは人でいっぱいの船です
If you remember the so-called
いわゆる
Our Memory of Vietnamese Refugees
ベトナム難民の記憶
so-called boat people
所謂的船民
Probably such an image
たぶんそんなイメージ
And the funniest thing is this
そして最も面白いのはこれです
This group doesn't just stuff the boat
このグループはただ船を詰め込むだけではありません
and in
そしてで
How to say
どのように言って
not just on board
船上だけではなく
on a boat full of people
人がいっぱいの船の上で
Seeking this place to dock in the middle of the ocean
海の真ん中に停泊できる場所を探しています
So in flight or in flight there is death
つまり、逃走中にも逃走中にも死は存在する
in danger while fleeing
逃走中に危険にさらされる
what about when you arrive
到着したらどうですか
After arriving, in the upper right corner is a photo of the refugee camp
到着後、右上隅に難民キャンプの写真が表示されます
then in the refugee camp
それから難民キャンプで
Actually these people live in tents
実はこの人たちはテントで暮らしているんです
Then it is very likely that these people are in our impression
そうすると、これらの人々が私たちの印象に残っている可能性が非常に高いです
The so-called refugees are also people with darker skin.
いわゆる難民も肌の色が黒い人たちです。
In fact, if you take a closer look at the ethnicity of Afghanistan
実際、アフガニスタンの民族性を詳しく見てみると、
or a false race
あるいは偽りの人種
They may not all be so dark.
それらすべてがそれほど暗いわけではないかもしれません。
But in our current understanding and experience of refugees
しかし、難民に対する私たちの現在の理解と経験では、
I'm afraid it's the same as us for the so-called
いわゆる、私たちと同じではないかと思います。
Weak or poor countries are of the view that
弱い国や貧しい国は次のように考えています。
or imagine being combined
または組み合わされることを想像してください
So what I want to emphasize in these photos is
この写真で私が強調したいのは、
This is a group photo with no faces
これは顔のない集合写真です
This is a reality that can be seen as miserable or tragic
これは悲惨とも悲劇的にも見える現実です
And this one is actually the one on the right, which may be the Naiming we most often see or may meet
そして、これは実際には右側にあるもので、これが私たちが最もよく見る、または遭遇するかもしれないナイミングかもしれません
But it's often the people we can't see
でも、それは多くの場合、私たちには見えない人々です
Either they live in the camp far away from us
彼らは私たちから遠く離れたキャンプに住んでいるかのどちらかです
Or they might just hang out with us
あるいは、彼らは私たちとただ一緒に過ごすかもしれない
But it never occurred to us that they might come from somewhere else
しかし、彼らが別の場所から来るかもしれないとは思いもしませんでした
Or we might recognize them from somewhere else
あるいは、別の場所からそれらを認識できるかもしれません
But we don't understand what his past and experience are
しかし、私たちは彼の過去と経験が何であるかを理解していません
Then this goes into, for example, the experience of Naiming.
次に、これはたとえばナイミンの経験に入ります。
probably a lot about narrating this thing
おそらくこのことを語るのに多くのことが関わっているでしょう
How to tell Namin's story so that they can be accepted
ナミンの話を受け入れてもらうにはどうすればよいか
How to describe his own experience so that his trauma can be alleviated
トラウマを軽減するために自分の経験をどう説明するか
How do you describe your experience so that you can meet the requirements of the International Rescue Agency?
国際救助機関の要件を満たすために、あなたの経験をどのように説明しますか?
the required image and be able to obtain certain assistance
必要な画像を取得し、特定の支援を得ることができる
These are actually stories from Naiming’s experience
これらは実際にナイミンの経験に基づいた物語です
plays a very important role
非常に重要な役割を果たします
exactly like his politics
まさに彼の政治と同じだ
OK
OK
So simply a little bit in this
それで、これに少しだけ
This is for refugees under the context of the United Nations
これは国連の文脈に基づく難民のためのものです
Judgment or specification to do a simple combing
簡易ソートを行うための判断または指定
Then we go into
それでは、
in other stories
他の話では
On the left is this so-called 1948
左側はいわゆる1948年のものです
human rights convention
人権条約
then at the beginning
それから最初に
In fact, what I want to emphasize is probably that
実際、私が強調したいのは、おそらく、
We all agree that human rights are a
私たちは皆、人権が重要であることに同意します。
human beings are born
人間は生まれる
In this convention, the specification is as follows
この規約では、仕様は次のようになります。
It is an inherent dignity
それは生来の尊厳である
man as man
男としての男
A kind of dignity that should have or will have
持つべき、あるいは持つであろう一種の尊厳
and is one that cannot
そしてそれはできないものです
are equal
は同じ
And it is an inalienable right
そしてそれは譲渡できない権利です
As long as you are a member of human society
人間社会の一員である限り
you have these things
あなたはこれらのものを持っています
What about this thing?
これについてはどうですか？
about liberty about justice about one of the most basic foundations of world peace
自由について 正義について 世界平和の最も基本的な基盤の一つについて
I'll put one like this in a moment about the so-called refugee status
いわゆる難民ステータスについて、このようなものをすぐに載せます。
And these discussions about these so-called freedoms and military exercises that they surround refugees so-called derived from
そして、難民を取り囲むいわゆる自由と軍事演習に関するこれらの議論は、いわゆる難民から派生したものです。
give a more in-depth explanation
より詳しい説明をする
But for now let's just walk through a simple illustration like this
ここでは、このような簡単な図を見てみましょう。
Then he said that in this so-called
それから彼はこのいわゆる
at the end
最後に
The last part he said
彼が言った最後の部分
If people don't want to be forced to have other
人々が他のものを強制されたくない場合は、
Forced to resort to measures as a last resort to rebel against oppression and hegemony
圧制と覇権に反逆する最後の手段として手段を講じざるを得なくなる
Then human rights must be protected through legal norms
その場合、人権は法的規範によって保護されなければなりません
This is referred to in the Human Rights Convention
これは人権条約で言及されています
Why human rights matter because
なぜ人権が重要なのかというと、
If people don't want these people
もし人々がこれらの人々を望まないなら
take a violent and drastic action
暴力的で大胆な行動をとる
to overthrow the government
政府を転覆させる
If you come to protest, to carry out acts of violence,
抗議し、暴力行為をしに来てください
Then we need to protect the human rights of these people
ならば、私たちはこれらの人々の人権を守らなければなりません
I think there is a hidden
隠しがあると思う
A paradox in the relationship between the state and the people
国家と国民の関係における矛盾
This is when we talk about human rights today
今日私たちが人権について話すときは、
A subject that is often likely to be encountered first
最初に遭遇する可能性が高い主題
but i'll come back here later
でも後でここに戻ってきます
on the right is
右側は
In 1951, the United Nations Refugee Agency formulated
1951年に国連難民機関は次のように定めました。
Regarding these treaties related to this so-called refugee
このいわゆる難民に関連するこれらの条約については、
Well here is a
さて、ここにあります
A definition of the word refugee
難民という言葉の定義
What did he call a refugee?
彼は難民を何と呼んでいましたか?
In addition to the above is to want to be in these specific time points
上記に加えて、これらの特定の時点にいたいこともあります
Those who are recognized as refugees are other than refugees
難民として認定される人は難民以外の人です
There is also an expanded definition in the second clause below
以下の 2 番目の条項にも拡張された定義があります。
that is
あれは
if they were
もし彼らがそうであれば
If they have concerns about being
懸念がある場合は、
because of their race, religion, nationality
彼らの人種、宗教、国籍のせいで
or the identity of a particular social group
または特定の社会集団のアイデンティティ
or his political opinions
または彼の政治的意見
And if you have fear or worry about being oppressed or persecuted
抑圧されたり迫害されたりするのではないかと恐れたり心配したりする場合
Or leave his own country
あるいは自分の国を離れるか
or other than nationality
または国籍以外
or there is no way because of fear
あるいは怖くて仕方がない
or unwilling to allow themselves to be protected by the state
または国家によって保護されることを望まない
And left the place where he used to live
そして彼は以前住んでいた場所を去りました
These people seek elsewhere
この人たちは別の場所を探します
seek settlement opportunities
和解の機会を求める
in such a situation
そのような状況で
These people can be called refugees
こういう人たちは難民と呼ばれるかもしれない
because they can't
彼らはできないから
Because they are unable or unwilling to return to their country of origin
出身国に戻ることができない、または戻る気がないため
Well, to put it simply, what needs to be emphasized here is probably that
まあ、簡単に言えば、ここで強調しなければならないのは、おそらく
The Difference Between So-Called Immigrants and Refugees
いわゆる移民と難民の違い
Immigration means you can come back after you leave
入国管理とは、出国後に再び戻ってくることができることを意味します
A refugee is when you leave and don't come back
難民とは、出国したまま戻ってこないことを指します
Then here we can see
それではここで見てみましょう
to a certain kind of refugee or immigrant
ある種の難民または移民に対して
In fact, there is a relationship that overlaps but differs
実は重なっているようで違う関係がある
So here's a quick look at
ここで簡単に見てみましょう
In the past few years, in the relevant statistics of the United Nations refugee category
過去数年間、国連難民カテゴリーの関連統計では、
the real situation of some refugees
一部の難民の実際の状況
For example, in the world
たとえば、世の中では
The forcibly displaced population has reached
強制的に避難させられた人口は
I'm not good at math
私は数学が苦手です
This should be about 89 million yuan
これは約8900万元になるはずです
that's a very, very high number
それは非常に高い数字です
then the next
それから次
For example in this
たとえばこれでは
Among the so-called low- and middle-income countries
いわゆる低・中所得国の中で
they refugees
彼らは難民です
83% of low- and middle-income countries
低中所得国の 83%
In fact, they have become places for these refugees.
実際、それらは難民の場所となっています。
Then there are 72% of refugees
それから難民の72％がいる
In fact, he was taken in in a neighboring country.
実は彼は隣国に引き取られていたのだ。
or temporarily stopped
または一時停止
And then let's say in Verenea which is a very special case
そして、非常に特殊なケースであるヴェレネアの場合を考えてみましょう。
One out of every six is ​​actually a refugee
6人に1人が実際に難民
Then stay on a small island in South America like Aruba, the so-called China Travel Island.
その後、中国旅行島と呼ばれるアルバのような南米の小さな島に滞在します。
And what surprised me the most is that a country like Türkiye
そして私が最も驚いたのは、トゥルキエのような国です。
A country that may not seem particularly advanced to us actually hosts 3.8 million refugees
私たちにとって特に先進的とは思えないこの国が、実際には380万人の難民を受け入れている
This is also a very astonishing number
これも非常に驚くべき数字です
Then every year, for example, there are 1.4 million refugee applications in the United States to become refugees
そして、たとえば、米国では毎年140万件の難民申請が行われています。
To become a refugee is not enough to say that I am a refugee, you have to apply and be recognized and accepted
難民になるには、「私は難民です」と言うだけでは十分ではありません。申請して認められ、受け入れられる必要があります。
Then, of course, I think the world on the right is very interesting.
そうすると、もちろん、右の世界もすごく面白いと思います。
Or should I say something very important
それとも何か大事なことを言うべきですか
very important one this
これはとても重要なことです
The numbers mean that among the world's population
この数字は、世界の人口のうち、
Children make up 30%
子どもが30％を占める
But among these forced displaced
しかし、こうした強制避難民の中には、
41% of the population is children
人口の41%が子供
So you can imagine that among these displaced people
想像できると思いますが、これらの避難民の中には、
most of nearly half of
ほぼ半分のほとんど
actually a minor
実は未成年
ok
Ok
These data are just for everyone to understand
これらのデータは誰もが理解できるようにするためのものです
That is to say, from the data
つまりデータから
Refugees are a very real
難民は本当に現実的なものです
And this problem that is happening
そして今起きているこの問題
And the refugee problem is a big one
そして難民問題は大きな問題です
facing several difficulties
いくつかの困難に直面している
one of course is to say
一つはもちろん言うことです
Do you want to accept refugees?
難民を受け入れたいですか？
Do you want to accept it, how to accept it, how to choose or not to choose
受け入れたいか、受け入れ方、選ぶか選ばないか。
If you don't let them all in
全部入れないと
Then how to arrange these people
では、この人たちをどうやって配置するかというと、
after settling down
落ち着いてから
what happens to these people
この人たちに何が起こるのか
how long will this placement take
この配置にはどのくらい時間がかかりますか
How to solve the problem of refugees
難民問題をどう解決するか
In today's Europe and America
今のヨーロッパやアメリカでは
It's actually a huge debate.
それは実際には大きな議論です。
especially in europe
特にヨーロッパでは
Then I can discuss this in detail later.
それでは、これについては後ほど詳しく説明します。
So let's move on to the topic of refugees
それでは難民の話に移りましょう
Especially in the context of our East Asia
特に東アジアという文脈においては
There are probably two parts that I particularly want to mention
特に言及したい部分はおそらく 2 つあります
One is what is the reason for the movement of refugees
一つは、難民の移動の理由は何か。
why do these refugees show up
なぜ難民が現れるのか
The second is the relationship between refugees and the history of our place
2つ目は、難民と私たちの場所の歴史との関係です。
Is there any clear and specific relationship?
明確で具体的な関係はあるのでしょうか？
For example, from the history of the Vietnam War
例えば、ベトナム戦争の歴史から
Obviously, including in Syria or in Afghanistan
明らかに、シリアやアフガニスタンも含めて
War is actually one of the reasons for the large number of refugees
実は戦争も大量の難民の原因の一つ
Of course, there are other
もちろん他にもあるよ
Including Tianhou, this change in climate
天后も含めて、この気候の変化
Also, for example, hunger
また、例えば飢餓
We'll probably mention this later
これについてはおそらく後で言及するでしょう
This example from North Korea
この北朝鮮の例
In fact, a lot of it is related to hunger.
実際、そのほとんどは飢餓に関係しています。
But politics is also an important factor
しかし、政治も重要な要素です
What's more interesting is that
さらに興味深いのは、
What happens when refugees appear because of the war?
戦争で難民が出たらどうなるのでしょうか？
The rescue of refugees is only related to the existence of the base
難民救出は基地の存在だけで決まる
There is a certain connection
あるつながりがある
For example, the photo on the right
たとえば、右の写真
It's actually in this place in San Diego, USA.
実はアメリカのサンディエゴにあるこの場所にあるんです。
There is one called Campandleton
カンパンドルトンと呼ばれるものがあります
It's actually a Marine Corps base.
実は海兵隊の基地なんです。
And in 1975 the outskirts of the base
そして1975年、基地の郊外
Just set up the refugee forest below
下に難民の森を設置するだけです
As a facility to receive these refugees from Taonan, Vietnam
ベトナム桃南省からの難民受け入れ施設として
That is, here we can see
つまり、ここでわかります
The movement of refugees is actually the same as the movement of the military
難民の移動は実は軍隊の移動と同じである
It has a state that cooperates with or intersects with each other
互いに連携または交差する状態を持っています
as if we just thought of
まるで私たちがたった今考えたかのように
For example, in the experience of Afghanistan
たとえば、アフガニスタンの経験では、
These refugees actually just left on a U.S. military plane.
これらの難民は実際には米軍機で出国したばかりです。
So at this time, let us think of a question
そこで今回は、ある質問を考えてみましょう
So what is the relationship between these military interventions and humanitarian assistance?
では、こうした軍事介入と人道支援との間にはどのような関係があるのでしょうか？
Then these refugees who were rescued
そして救出された難民たちは
or accepted refugees
または受け入れられた難民
Are they enemies or allies?
彼らは敵ですか、それとも味方ですか？
Are you a foreigner or a compatriot?
あなたは外国人ですか、それとも同胞ですか?
Then this is the only one in Vietnam
そうするとベトナムではここだけです
These refugees speak from the experience of immigrants in the United States
これらの難民は米国での移民の経験から語ります
so strong
とても強い
Because after the fall of Saigon in 1975
1975年のサイゴン陥落後だから
refugees coming to america
アメリカに来る難民
In the hearts of many Americans
多くのアメリカ人の心の中に
refugees from vietnam
ベトナムからの難民
and most likely their enemies
そしておそらく彼らの敵
But the reason why these people can come to the United States
しかし、これらの人々が米国に来ることができる理由は、
Precisely because they used to be in the U.S. military
彼らはかつて米軍にいたからこそ
Be their ally in Vietnam time
ベトナム時間で彼らの味方になってください
or their translator
またはその翻訳者
Or their other places that match these
またはこれらに一致する他の場所
Or simply put, these South Vietnamese regimes
簡単に言えば、これらの南ベトナム政権は
person
人
They had the opportunity to come to Vietnam
彼らはベトナムに来る機会がありました
sorry for coming to america
アメリカに来てごめんなさい
So in this sense
ですから、そういう意味では
All refugee movements are related to the military
すべての難民の動きは軍と関係がある
In fact, it is worth our deep thinking
実際、深く考えてみる価値はある
It's also worth thinking about
それも考える価値があります
For the identity of those who move
移動する人の身元確認のため
In fact, it often follows us
実際、それはしばしば私たちを追いかけます
Judgments about politics are relevant
政治に関する判断は重要です
further in Taiwan
さらに台湾へ
what is our own experience with refugees
私たち自身の難民に関する経験は何ですか
In fact, not long ago, this documentary was screened on official business
実はつい最近、このドキュメンタリーが公務で上映されました。
It is said that there is a Jiangmei camp in Baisha, Penghu.
澎湖県白沙に江美陣営があるという。
Once in 1978 to 1988
1978年から1988年に一度
It is a refugee camp received as this so-called Vietnamese descendant refugees
このいわゆるベトナム系難民として受け入れられた難民キャンプです
Well, this Jiangmei camp is actually
さて、この江美キャンプは実は
This is the original
これがオリジナルです
It is also the army or the camp where the army is stationed nearby
軍隊または軍隊が近くに駐留するキャンプでもあります
So again we see this relationship between a military and this refugee camp
そこで再び軍と難民キャンプの関係がわかります
But what's more, it's
しかし、さらに、それは、
The existence of this camp is actually in our memory
このキャンプの存在は実際に私たちの記憶にあります
In fact, especially for young people, they may never have thought of such a thing.
実際、特に若い人にとっては、そんなこと考えたこともないかもしれません。
So this director Liu Jixiong and his team
つまり、このディレクター、Liu Jixiong と彼のチームは、
In fact, it took a lot of effort to rearrange and introduce such a history
実は、このような歴史を整理して紹介するには大変な労力がかかりました
allows us to see that in 1975
1975年にそれを見ることができます
After the fall of Vietnam in 1975
1975年のベトナム崩壊後
In fact, Taiwan is also participating in the entire anti-communist camp.
実際、台湾も反共陣営全体に参加している。
played a humanitarian role
人道的な役割を果たした
Although not particularly prominent
特別目立ったわけではないものの、
But it's also part of our history
しかし、それも私たちの歴史の一部です
But it is often not remembered
でも覚えていないことも多い
It is very interesting that in these coming to Taiwan these
非常に興味深いのは、これらが台湾に来ていることです。
Vietnamese refugees
ベトナム難民
Actually there are some good parts
実は良い部分もあるんです
In fact, the so-called Chinese
実は、いわゆる中国人は、
So this involves the whole of this guy in Vietnam
これにはベトナムにいるこの男全員が関係している
this so-called
これはいわゆる
Vietnam’s socialist identity actually includes Chinese
ベトナムの社会主義者としてのアイデンティティには中国人も含まれている
Chinese are also a very important presence
中国人もとても重要な存在です
And the Chinese are also in this process
そして中国人もこの過程にいます
Come to Taiwan or even stay
台湾に来てもいいし、滞在してもいい
Of course a large part also
もちろん大きな部分も
Passed through Taiwan to other places
台湾を経由して各地へ
So this batch
それでこのバッチ
Refugee compatriots in the atmosphere of the times at that time
当時の時代の雰囲気の中にいる難民同胞たち
Are they treated as refugees or as compatriots?
彼らは難民として扱われるのでしょうか、それとも同胞として扱われるのでしょうか？
Or possessed person or own person
または憑依された人または自分自身
They are refugees surviving in the dry sea
彼らは乾いた海で生き残る難民です
Still regardless of some for the sake of freedom and democracy
自由と民主主義のため、それでも一部の人には構わない
And the anti-communist consciousness that came to Taiwan
そして台湾に伝わった反共意識
Then I ask these few questions
それから私はこれらのいくつかの質問をします
In fact, I keep wanting to outline
実際、私は概要を説明したいと思っています
Probably through the refugees
おそらく難民を通じて
stories and history
物語と歴史
how to rethink
どうやって考え直すか
in this through the refugees
この中で難民を通して
Nearby we can see
近くで私たちは見ることができます
Political, military and humanitarian assistance
政治的、軍事的、人道的支援
very complicated relationship
非常に複雑な関係
that soon i want to pass
すぐに合格したい
A few stories from North Korea
北朝鮮からのいくつかの物語
talk to you further
さらに話してください
This so-called refugee
このいわゆる難民は、
The relationship between refugees and stories
難民と物語の関係
Let's put it this way
このようにしましょう
I chose these three works
この３作品を選びました
I won't go into specific details
具体的な詳細には触れません
but i think it's worth it
でもそれだけの価値はあると思う
Let me explain to you a little bit
少し説明させてください
This one on the left is called Puyanmei
左側のこれはプヤンメイと呼ばれるものです
Actually
実際
If you are on facebook
フェイスブックを利用している場合
or easily found on Google
または Google で簡単に見つかります
his photo
彼の写真
Because he published such a book
こんな本を出版したから
In order to live this book
この本を生きるために
Also has translation in Chinese
中国語の翻訳もあります
And then translated many other languages
その後、他の多くの言語を翻訳しました
It has been followed up and several books have been published.
その後も研究が進められ、何冊か本が出版されています。
The book is basically one of its own as a North Korean refugee
この本は基本的に北朝鮮難民に関する独自の本である
So-called
所謂的
Testimonial A Testimonial and Narrative
お客様の声 A お客様の声と物語
So
それで
Of course it now puts
もちろん今は入れています
what should i say
私は何を言えばいい
that is
あれは
This testimony and narrative speaks for itself
この証言と物語はそれ自体を物語っています
such an experience
そのような経験
Then in the middle this one is a
それから真ん中にこれがあります
Korean-American writer named Chris Lee
クリス・リーという韓国系アメリカ人作家
Wrote a novel written in 2013
2013年に小説を書きました
叫做 How I Became a North Korean
叫んで私はどのようにして北朝鮮人になったのか
that's how i became a north korean
こうして私は北朝鮮人になった
This part of the novel is about
小説のこの部分については、
On the border between China and North Korea
中国と北朝鮮の国境で
this we now understand
これは私たちが今理解していることです
It is the serious emergency on the China-North Korea border
中朝国境は深刻な緊急事態だ
Then strictly border this ethnic knowledge area
そして、この民族知識領域を厳密に境界づけます
such a space
そんな空間
In fact, there were many in the 90s
実際90年代にはたくさんあったよ
There are many North Korean refugees
北朝鮮難民がたくさんいる
From North Korea to China
北朝鮮から中国に来た
so so this story
それでこの話
It was in such a 90's
そんな90年代にありました
North Korean refugees North Korean refugees to China in the background
北朝鮮難民 中国への北朝鮮難民を背景に
to talk about a Korean in China
中国にいる韓国人のことを話す
Actually went to America
実際にアメリカに行ってきました
And then back to the border between China and North Korea
そして再び中国と北朝鮮の国境へ
saw or encountered these refugees
これらの難民に会った、または遭遇した
And because of China's opportunity
そして中国のチャンスのせいで
Also considered part of the refugees
難民の一部ともみなされる
So How I Became North Korean
それで私はどのようにして北朝鮮人になったのか
It's actually about showing an immigrant turned refugee.
実際には、移民から難民になった人物を描くものです。
Such an interesting but complicated relationship
とても興味深いけれど複雑な関係
Then the novel on the right is a translation of
そして、右の小説は、の翻訳です
It was originally a novel written by a Korean writer in Korean
元々は韓国の作家が韓国語で書いた小説でした
then translated into english
それから英語に翻訳されました
It's called I met...
会ったって言うのは…
Can't see Beauty now
今はビューティーが見れない
I met Loki on Loki
ロキでロキに会った
It’s just that Beauty is very simple, that is, I met a person like Logic Magic
ただ、美しさはとてもシンプルです、つまりロジックマジックのような人に出会ったのです
Logical fantasy is actually in this story
この物語にはロジカルファンタジーが実はある
The refugee who didn't show up until the very end
最後まで現れなかった難民
But this story...
でもこの話は…
The protagonist is actually a journalist in Korea
主人公は実は韓国のジャーナリスト。
He saw this one about logic sickness
彼は論理障害に関するこれを見た
This is the introduction of Escape
エスケープの紹介です
And there is a touch to go after him
そして彼を追いかける気配がある
What is the experience of being a refugee?
難民としての経験とは何ですか？
Then this probably has something to do with what happened to him in the story.
そうなると、これはおそらく物語の中で彼に起こったことと関係があるでしょう。
Personal experience has an interesting contrast
個人的な経験には興味深い対照がある
But I'll leave this part for now
でも、この部分は今は置いておきます
The reason why we talk about these three is because
なぜこの 3 つについて話すかというと、
One is the self-narration of the refugees themselves, right?
一つは難民自身の自語りですよね？
The other is through a very external perspective
もう 1 つは非常に外部的な視点によるものです
To imagine being on the border between China and North Korea
中国と北朝鮮の国境にいると想像する
Possible Refugee Opportunities and Correlations
考えられる難民の機会と相関関係
And the other one is actually a projection entirely at a distance.
そしてもう 1 つは、実際には完全に遠くにある投影です。
But through this projection he initiated a process of seeking refugees
しかし、この投影を通じて、彼は難民を探すプロセスを開始しました。
one of these three stories
この3つの物語のうちの1つ
The juxtaposition actually presents an interesting
この並列配置は実際に興味深いものを示しています
triangle structure
三角構造
that refugees are often in the story
つまり、物語には難民がよく登場するのです
Well
良い
Among all the refugee stories on the Internet
インターネット上のあらゆる難民の話の中で
He is often the one who is forced to
と強要されるのは彼であることが多い。
should say so
そう言うべきだ
He is often the one imagined
彼はしばしば想像通りの人です
But at the same time he was placed in a specific position
しかし同時に彼は特定の立場に置かれた
to express refugees
難民を表現する
I'm not very clear about this
これについてはよくわかりません
I simply put it this way
単純にこう言いました
as a refugee
難民として
He was actually expected to tell a story about him
彼は実際、自分についての話をすることを期待されていた
And the story that is expected to be told
そして語られることが期待される物語
has his script
彼の台本がある
For example we will see later
たとえば、後で説明します
here it will be
ここにあります
I skip here first
まずここをスキップします
It's clearer here
こちらのほうがわかりやすいですね
For example, the author Pu Yanmei is a North Korean defector
たとえば、著者のプー・ヤンメイは脱北者である。
also a human rights fighter
人権闘争家でもある
his story is
彼の話は
His story brings people together
彼の物語は人々を結びつける
Behind the Iron Curtain regime in North Korea
北朝鮮の鉄のカーテン体制の裏側
The life of ordinary people
普通の人々の生活
This is a video of him and his family trying to escape North Korea
これは彼と彼の家族が北朝鮮から脱出しようとしているビデオです
Overcoming the pressure of freezing
凍結の圧力を克服する
Will escape the clutches of ex-pats and gangsters
駐在員やギャングの手から逃れるだろう
Into the Gobi Desert to Mongolia
ゴビ砂漠からモンゴルへ
Defector's story on the flight to South Korea
韓国行きの飛行機での脱北者の話
If you read the introduction of such a book
こういう本の紹介文を読むと
you will find wow
あなたはすごいことを見つけるでしょう
it's simply a
それは単に
an adventure story isn't it
冒険物語じゃないですか
then this adventure story
それからこの冒険物語
It is actually going to outline
実際に概要を説明していきます
such a thrilling escape
とてもスリリングな脱出
So so included here
だからここに含まれています
English is partly actually
実は英語は部分的には
An illustrated direction of the beginning of its story
物語の始まりを描いたイラスト
In the first paragraph it says
最初の段落にはこう書かれています
On the cold black night of March 31st
3月31日の寒い黒い夜に
at
で
This March 31, 2007
この2007年3月31日
such a cold night
とても寒い夜
my mother and me
私の母と私
This squats very low
これは非常に低くしゃがみます
Then press the green river
それから緑の川を押してください
this frozen green river
この凍った緑の川
crawling along the coast
海岸に沿って這う
This presses the green river to separate
これにより、緑の川が分離するよう圧力がかかります
North Korea and China
北朝鮮と中国
Well here are a lot of
さて、ここにはたくさんあります
Patrol guards in
巡回警備員
above and below us
私たちの上と下
and then these
そしてこれら
These guards will be here
これらの警備員はここにいます
per white foot
白い足ごとに
Sorry, what is the name of every two in Chinese?
すみません、2人全員の名前は中国語で何と言うのでしょうか？
scold each other for nothing
無駄にお互いを叱り合う
There will be these guards in this episode
このエピソードにはこれらの警備員が登場します
Then
それから
there will be soldiers and they say
兵士たちがいるだろう、そして彼らは言う
anytime to those involved in crossing the border
国境越えに関わる方々へいつでも
so so we don't know what's going to happen
だから、何が起こるかわかりません
We just want to leave North Korea and go to China in a positive way or in a very extreme way
私たちはただ北朝鮮を出て、前向きな方法、または非常に極端な方法で中国に行きたいだけです。
we might have a chance to survive
私たちには生き残るチャンスがあるかもしれない
The story of Napu Yanmei tells a very typical
ナプ・ヤンメイの物語は非常に典型的なものです。
We're almost a typical refugee
私たちはほぼ典型的な難民です
In fact, this typical refugee image also reflects the image of refugees.
実は、この典型的な難民像も難民のイメージを反映しています。
The story about refugees is placed in an almost stereotypical position
難民に関する物語はほぼ定型的な立場に置かれている
As a refugee, he must go through a lot of risks
難民として彼は多くのリスクを経験しなければならない
As a refugee he must have gone through all sorts of brutality
難民として彼はあらゆる種類の残虐行為を経験したに違いない
as a refugee he must be
彼は難民であるに違いない
OK
OK
Well, if you think about it, you will know
まあ、考えてみれば分かりますが、
The millions of refugees we just saw
私たちが今目にした何百万もの難民
In fact, not all have the same experience
実際には、誰もが同じ経験をしているわけではありません
In other words, everyone's experience cannot be compared with pain.
言い換えれば、誰もが経験することを痛みと比較することはできません。
OK
OK
Well, but we need or say that among these solemn
まあ、しかし、これらの厳粛な儀式の中で、私たちはそれを必要とするか、言います
but often as a reading
しかし多くの場合、読み物として
Perhaps more of what we are consuming is the suffering and experience of these people
おそらく私たちが消費しているものの多くは、これらの人々の苦しみと経験です
as one of our wonders
私たちの不思議の一つとして
So through this spectacle we inspired a
この光景を通して、私たちは次のようなインスピレーションを与えました。
A kind of sympathy for the suffering of refugees
難民の苦しみに対するある種の同情
Well, of course this is to a certain extent
まあ、もちろんある程度はそうなのですが、
Not necessarily a bad thing, right?
必ずしも悪いことではありませんよね？
because we can see
私たちには見えるから
In fact, we also have such an experience in our hearts.
実際、私たちも心の中にそのような経験を持っています。
It is possible to have a heart of silhouette
シルエットの心を持つことができる
And not because it's from, say, North Korea
それは例えば北朝鮮からのものだからではない
rather different
むしろ違う
But here I think a very interesting question is
しかし、ここで非常に興味深い質問があると思います。
Will we because it's because of North Korea
北朝鮮のせいだからやろうか
And think differently about such refugees
そして、そのような難民については違った考えを持ってください
Will we because of today's refugee
今日の難民のせいで私たちはできるだろうか
is from Syria or Afghanistan
シリアかアフガニスタン出身です
and think differently
そして違う考え方をする
I'm not asking this question as an answer
この質問は答えとして聞いているわけではありません
but a question
しかし質問です
Actually let's think about it
実際に考えてみましょう
When we're dealing with refugee stories and refugee status
難民の話や難民の地位を扱うとき
Do we have some inherited ideas and concepts
継承されたアイデアやコンセプトはありますか
These things are exactly what I hope through today's speech
これらはまさに私が今日のスピーチを通して望んでいることです
able to propose
提案できる
I brought it up to think with everyone
みんなで考えようと思い立ちました
ok then let's move on to this
さて、それではこれに移りましょう
How it Became North Korean
どのようにして北朝鮮になったのか
This is also in Guardian
これもガーディアンに載ってます
One of the British Guardian newspapers for this book
この本を取り上げた英国ガーディアン紙の 1 つ
brief introduction
簡単な紹介
let's take a look
見てみましょう
Most of these North Korean defectors
これらの脱北者のほとんどは、
We are in Chinese and we have a term called defector
私たちは中国語で「亡命者」という言葉があります。
or this rebel of politics
あるいはこの政治の反逆者
They came to North Korea where they left
彼らは出発した北朝鮮に来た
North Korea leaving via China
北朝鮮が中国経由で出国
At any given time
いつでも
There would be thousands of these refugees here
ここには何千人もの難民がいるだろう
hiding in this state of living in hiding
隠れて生きているこの状態で隠れて
Scared they might be caught and deported
逮捕されて国外追放されるのではないかと心配
Women may be trafficked into this
女性はこの中で人身売買される可能性がある
The so-called new workers or married people
いわゆる新社会人や既婚者
These Chinese farmers who can't get wives
妻をもてない中国の農民たち
Then men may be violently oppressed by this gangster and become a special park
その場合、男性はこの暴力団によって暴力的に抑圧され、特別な公園になる可能性があります
These teachers of the church, these teachers of the Jesuits may also
教会の教師たち、イエズス会の教師たちも、
Why, no matter what, they may come to aid and resettle these refugees
なぜ彼らは、何があろうとも、これらの難民を助け、定住させようとするのでしょうか。
But sometimes, they are treated as criminals.
しかし、時には犯罪者として扱われることもあります。
even force them to read the bible and ask them to change their religion
聖書を読むことを強制し、宗教を変えるよう求めることさえある
in exchange for their freedom, or their loyalty to the country
自由、あるいは国への忠誠と引き換えに
So he said this novel, he is among several different narrators
それで彼はこの小説をこう言いました、彼は数人の異なる語り手の一人です
Make an exchange where the male lead is called Yongju
男性主人公をヨンジュと呼ぶ交換をする
He's a kid who was supposed to be a high ranking North Korean general.
彼は北朝鮮の高位の将軍になるはずだった子供です。
Then because of this
じゃあこれのせいで
Killed for political reasons
政治的理由で殺された
So he and his mother fled
それで彼と母親は逃げた
and my sister escaped
そして妹は逃げた
During this escape
この逃亡中に
Mom and sister are lost
母と妹がいなくなった
He's left alone at the Chinese border
彼は中国国境に一人取り残された
stay above
上に留まる
Then the other one is called Johnny
それからもう一人はジョニーと呼ばれます
is a female
女性です
Then she was pregnant before fleeing.
その後、彼女は逃亡する前に妊娠していた。
so you can see
それでわかります
Just before this description
この説明の直前に
This part about this so called sex trafficking
いわゆる性的人身売買に関するこの部分
Maybe it's related to Johnny's story
もしかしたらジョニーの話と関係があるかもしれない
Then there is another fact that
それからもう一つの事実があります
the one we were talking about
私たちが話していたこと
originally grew up on the edge
もともと辺境で育った
then went to America
それからアメリカに行きました
back to the edge
端に戻る
During this experience
この体験中に
Accidentally mistaken for a North Korean
うっかり北朝鮮人と間違われてしまう
Such a person is called Danny
そのような人はダニーと呼ばれます
so so i think this story is very interesting
だから、この話はとても面白いと思います
He sees through this Danny's point of view
彼はダニーの視点を見抜いています
let's see say
言ってみましょう
when you don't have a passport
パスポートを持っていないとき
when you have no documents to prove
証明できる書類がないとき
who are you when
あなたはいつ誰ですか
in the Sino-Korean border
中韓国境で
you are likely to be treated as
あなたは次のように扱われる可能性があります
One who fled North Korea
北朝鮮から逃亡した人
Then this as a
それからこれは
is highly risky
非常に危険です
OK
OK
Then the only salvation is in this story
ならば唯一の救いはこの物語の中にある
The only salvation is through this assistance of the Church
唯一の救いは教会の援助によるものです
And the church has become another
そして教会は別のものになった
Another form of coercion for this institution
この機関に対する別の形態の強制
they may threaten you
彼らはあなたを脅迫するかもしれない
if you don't listen
聞かないと
hand you over to the police
あなたを警察に引き渡します
Or like this unit report in the locality, etc.
あるいは、この現地でのユニットレポートなど。
Then this is the description in the story
では、ストーリー内での説明はこんな感じです
Then I think these descriptions are also
それでは、これらの説明もそうだと思います
Based on my understanding and research
私の理解と調査によると
there are also some
いくつかもあります
basic
基本的な
Sometimes the writer actually did some research and investigation
ライターが実際にリサーチや調査を行った場合もあります
wrote such a story
そんな話を書きました
Then this story shows us another
そして、この物語は私たちに別のことを示します
This one from Taonan in front of this one
この前にある桃南産のこれ
Beyond the template and the typical
テンプレートや典型的なものを超えて
What is less noticed is that
あまり注目されていないのは、
A dialectical relationship between the seekers of the South and the rescuers
南を求める者と南を救う者との弁証法的な関係
And the core of this story is that Danny became the hero who saved everyone
そしてこの物語の核心は、ダニーがみんなを救ったヒーローになったということです
And why does he have such an ability
そしてなぜ彼はそのような能力を持っているのでしょうか
He actually grew up on the edge of a rock
彼は実際、崖っぷちで育った
So he also has a family background that can help
つまり、彼には役立つ家族背景もあります
He recovers his identity in the process of fleeing
彼は逃亡の過程で自分のアイデンティティを取り戻す
At the same time, he also rescued his fellow sufferers
同時に彼は苦しんでいる仲間たちも救った
I think the last story is also very interesting.
最終話もとても面白いと思います。
I'll introduce you soon
近々紹介します
In fact, it is about such a person as Locking One.
実際、それはロッキング・ワンのような人物に関するものです。
He is also a North Korean defector
彼も脱北者です
then in this story
それからこの物語の中で
I didn't describe how he defected from North Korea
彼がどのようにして北朝鮮から亡命したかについては説明しなかった
Just simply stating that he has experienced difficulties from scratch
ただ一から苦労を経験したと言うだけです
came to belgium
ベルギーに来ました
He came to Belgium without knowing a word of French
彼はフランス語を一言も知らずにベルギーに来た
I don't know how to live in this place
この場所でどうやって生きていけばいいのか分からない
He only has a few hundred euros in cash
彼は現金を数百ユーロしか持っていない
must live every day of his stay in belgium
彼はベルギー滞在中毎日を過ごさなければならない
through for this
このために
It is in this story that the heroine
この物語の中でヒロインは、
North Korean defector's recourse for this refugee
この難民に対する脱北者の救済手段
he experienced again
彼はまた経験した
This North Korean defector was in a Belgian
この脱北者はベルギーにいた
each step for example
たとえば各ステップ
How to get to the hotel where he stepped down at the time
当時降板したホテルへの行き方
To face those who may have been for this refugee at that time
当時この難民の味方だったかもしれない人々と向き合うために
Those who are not very polite in the interaction
あまり丁寧な対応ができない方
The hotel staff
ホテルのスタッフ
how to face the possibility
可能性にどう向き合うか
It's not the people who really bullied him back then.
当時彼を本当にいじめていたのは人々ではありません。
But in his experience
しかし彼の経験では
those who are very sure
とても確信している人たち
Very self-sustaining these European whites
非常に自立したヨーロッパの白人
Interacting with Asians
アジア人との交流
So in my opinion the story
私の意見では、この話は
actually put the story
実際にストーリーを載せる
In fact, using refugees as a figure
実際、難民を数字として使うと、
a clue
手掛かり
His clue allows readers as well as writers
彼の手がかりは、読者だけでなく作家にも可能にする
Be able to recount experiences that a refugee might have encountered
難民が遭遇したかもしれない経験を語ることができる
while putting yourself in
身を置きながら
in that experience
その経験の中で
in this sense
この意味で
He and the one in front
彼と前の人
I became North Korean
北朝鮮人になってしまった
a little bit like
少し似ています
In fact, we are all asking us to put ourselves
実際、私たちは自分自身を置きたいのです
plunge into that refugee experience
その難民体験に飛び込む
then in this sense
じゃあこの意味で
he left
彼は去った
he left on the one hand
彼は一方で立ち去った
This so-called third-person description
このいわゆる三人称の描写
also left a first-person
一人称も残した
The so-called subjective refugee
いわゆる主観的難民
spectacle self-narrative
スペクタクルの自己物語
Instead, it creates a
代わりに、
reflective space
反射スペース
let's think about it
それについて考えてみましょう
How to tell refugee stories
難民の物語をどう伝えるか
to be able to tell the stories of refugees
難民の物語を伝えることができるようになる
Three-dimensional
三次元
Speak well
うまく話します
To be able to make the refugee experience
難民体験ができるように
not just as a
としてだけではなく
to be consumed
消費される
but one that can help us
しかし、私たちを助けることができるもの
such a possibility of self-reflection
そういう反省の可能性もある
So in this story
それでこの話では
there is a very classic
非常に古典的なものがあります
very important in my opinion
私の意見では非常に重要です
and a part of the classic
そして古典の一部
That's Loki 1 in Belgium
それはベルギーのロキ1です
ended up staying very successfully
とてもうまく滞在できました
So I won't expand on the details of the head.
したがって、頭部の詳細については説明しません。
but what about after this stay
しかし、この滞在後はどうなるでしょうか
he is attending
彼は出席しています
Working in a restaurant, I met a guy from the Philippines
レストランで働いていて、フィリピンから来た男性と出会いました
illegal immigrant
不法滞在者
That's because of this illegal immigrant woman from the Philippines
それはフィリピンからの不法移民女性のせいだ
don't speak french
フランス語を話さないでください
So he always wanted to go to an English-speaking country
それで彼はいつも英語圏の国に行きたいと思っていました
After Lokkawang met her
ロッカワンが彼女と出会ってから
The two of them are actually just this colleague in the restaurant
二人は実はレストランの同僚に過ぎない
But the application for a long time
しかし、長い間アプリケーション
So when this girl decides to go to England
それで、この女の子がイギリスに行くことを決めたとき
Lokkawang is also disregarding himself
ロッカワンも自分を無視している
Willing to follow her to England
彼女を追ってイギリスまで行きたい
So for the heroine of the story, the narrator,
つまり、物語のヒロインである語り手にとって、
He thought it was an unimaginable thing
彼はそれは想像もできないことだと思った
He had a hard time getting out of his refugee status.
彼は難民状態から抜け出すのに苦労しました。
why is he willing to let go
なぜ彼は手放そうとするのか
The chance to finally get settled in this Belgium
ついにこのベルギーに定住するチャンス
And once again became a refugee and ran to
そして再び難民となって、
Or at least an illegal immigrant to the UK?
それとも少なくとも英国への不法移民でしょうか？
In the course of this pursuit, he discovered that
この追求の過程で、彼は発見した
it's actually really easy
実はとても簡単です
Because in their step by step
なぜなら、彼らは一歩一歩進んでいるからです
in the process of creating your own life
自分の人生を創造していく過程で
They're no longer the subsidized, doled out refugee
彼らはもはや補助金を受けて寄付された難民ではない
In the process of no longer being self-reliant and self-reliant
自立も自立もできなくなっていく過程で
These refugees have their own dignity
これらの難民には独自の尊厳がある
He knows he can live like everyone else
彼は自分が他の人と同じように生きられることを知っている
Learning another language is hard work
他の言語を学ぶのは大変な作業です
Adapting to another environment is not easy
別の環境に適応するのは簡単ではない
But this provides an opportunity for them to strengthen themselves
しかし、これは彼らに自分自身を強化する機会を提供します
So so I want to pass through these few stories
それでは、これらのいくつかの物語を通過したいと思います
What I want to outline is probably such a simple thing
私が概説したいことはおそらくとても単純なことです
that's what we know about refugees
それが難民について私たちが知っていることです
cannot just stay at one
一つだけにとどまることはできない
In the relationship between the recipient and the sympathizer
受け手と共感者の関係において
At the same time, our experience with refugees cannot only be
同時に、難民に対する私たちの経験は、
treat it as outside this visible window
この可視ウィンドウの外側として扱います
such an invisible being
そんな目に見えない存在
They are likely to be around in our daily life
それらは私たちの日常生活の中に存在する可能性があります
maybe as we know these
おそらく私たちが知っているように
The so-called migrant workers from Southeast Asia are also good
いわゆる東南アジアからの出稼ぎ労働者もいいですね
or the previous
または以前の
others from different places
他の人は別の場所から
These moving crowds of different cultures are also good
こういう異文化の感動的な群衆も良いですね
Not necessarily in our extreme vision
必ずしも私たちの極端なビジョンではありません
But they are equally important
しかし、それらも同様に重要です
They are also fighting for their freedom and dignity.
彼らはまた、自由と尊厳のために戦っています。
Soon I will provide a little bit of good context
すぐに少し良いコンテキストを提供します
Let everyone understand why North Korean Namin is in my discussion
なぜ北朝鮮のナミンが私の議論に加わっているのかみんなに理解してもらいましょう
play a relatively important role
比較的重要な役割を果たす
On the one hand, if you still remember the numbers I mentioned earlier,
一方で、先ほど述べた数字をまだ覚えている方は、
Stories about the Vietnam War
ベトナム戦争についての話
In fact, the whole Vietnam War story is an anti-Communist story
実際、ベトナム戦争の物語全体は反共産主義の物語である
if we can
できれば
A slightly rough word for understanding
理解するための少し乱暴な言葉
So so today we are imagining
それで今日も私たちは想像しています
when North Korea or North Korea
北朝鮮か北朝鮮のとき
In fact, the supporters of North Korea are often placed in a
実際、北朝鮮の支持者はしばしば、
To understand from the anti-communist narrative
反共産主義の物語から理解する
These people turn north means they are against Kim Jong Un's regime
これらの人々が北に向かうということは、彼らが金正恩政権に反対していることを意味する
Against such a state of North Korea
そんな北朝鮮の現状に対して
The freedom they fought for was in a larger sense
彼らが勝ち取った自由は、より広い意味でのものだった
It affirms the value of democracy and freedom
民主主義と自由の価値を確認します
But if you look closely at these people
しかし、この人たちをよく見てみると、
The experience of these North Koreans who came to South Korea
韓国に来た北朝鮮人の体験
When you come to experience in different places
いろいろな場所に体験に来たら
you realize
あなたは気づいています
that democracy and freedom
その民主主義と自由
In fact, it is not as tolerant as imagined
実際は想像ほど寛容ではない
Actually asked these people
実際にこの人たちに聞いてみた
conform to a particular image
特定のイメージに適合する
provide a specific function
特定の機能を提供する
No matter what we talked about in the early years
最初の頃に何を話したとしても
An imagination of anti-communist consciousness
反共意識の想像力
Or today we talk about North Korean defectors
それとも今日は脱北者について話しますか
or some other attempt at such expression
またはそのような表現の他の試み
In fact, to a certain extent
実際、ある程度までは
Otherize this so-called refugee
このいわゆる難民を他者化する
Othering means
その他の手段
There is actually a distance between you and me
実はあなたと私の間には距離があるのです
I can see you so much
すごく見えるよ
But that distance exists
でもその距離は存在する
of course here
もちろんここで
So to simplify the context of this detail
この詳細のコンテキストを単純化するために、
That is to say, during the period from 1994 to 1998
つまり、1994 年から 1998 年にかけて
In fact, there was a big famine in North Korea
実は北朝鮮では大飢饉があった
Then in this frenzied state
そしてこの狂った状態で
Many people left North Korea
多くの人が北朝鮮を離れた
Then this departure is for North Korea
それでは今回の出国は北朝鮮行きです
For the people before 1994
1994年以前の人にとっては
Before a big move
大きな動きの前に
Actually, it's not a serious matter for them.
実際、それは彼らにとって深刻な問題ではありません。
Because the border between China and North Korea is not so tight
中国と北朝鮮の国境はそこまで厳しくないから
a state of strict
厳しい状態
Many residents in North Korea
北朝鮮には多くの住民がいる
probably during the cultural revolution
おそらく文化大革命の頃
It happened to be the one who fled from the border to North Korea
たまたま国境から北朝鮮に逃亡した人だった
So these groups where a lot of people trade across the border
つまり、多くの人が国境を越えて取引するこれらのグループは、
It may also be in the process of border
国境通過中かも知れません
form a so-called cross-border group
いわゆる国境を越えたグループを形成する
Not to mention the so-called Koreans along the border
国境沿いに住むいわゆる韓国人は言うまでもない。
In fact, in a long historical context, in the rainy environment of Northeast Asia
実際、長い歴史の中で、北東アジアの雨の多い環境では、
In fact, there are many cross-border mobile
実際、国境を越えたモバイルはたくさんあります。
So it's actually the border that separates the two sides.
つまり、実際にはそれが両側を隔てる境界線なのです。
In other words, the state system actually separates the people living on the border
言い換えれば、国家制度は実際に国境に住む人々を隔離しているということだ。
Then in the context of the 1990s
それから1990年代の文脈では
Those who escaped from North Korea
北朝鮮から逃亡した人たち
In many cases, it will be regarded as a so-called economic immigrant.
いわゆる経済移民とみなされる場合が多いでしょう。
But in China there is no way to recognize them as economic immigrants
しかし中国では彼らを経済移民として認識する方法はない
Because there is actually a treaty of friendship between China and North Korea
実際に中国と北朝鮮の間には友好条約があるからです
What this treaty subsequently stipulates or requires is
この条約がその後規定または要求するのは、
China should not be concerned about the stability of this regime in North Korea
中国は北朝鮮のこの政権の安定を懸念すべきではない
pose any threat
何らかの脅威をもたらす
So if China accepts these fleeing refugees as economic immigrants
では、もし中国がこれらの逃亡難民を経済移民として受け入れたら
To some extent, the above is the opposite.
ある意味、上記とは逆です。
The political situation and economic instability in North Korea
北朝鮮の政治情勢と経済不安
As a result, possible conflicts between the two countries
その結果、両国間に紛争が起こる可能性がある
Then it is also impossible for him to admit that they are so-called defectors
そうすると、彼らがいわゆる脱北者であることを認めることもできない。
is to defect from North Korea
北朝鮮から亡命することです
politics
政治
the rebellion
反乱
not a rebellion
反乱ではない
meaning in politics
政治における意味
Because it also shows that China may become accommodating North Korea
それは中国が北朝鮮に融和的になる可能性があることを示しているからでもある
a space of meaning molecules
意味分子の空間
So in this sense
ですから、そういう意味では
Whether it's a North Korean defector
脱北者かどうか
It doesn't matter if it's meaningful
意味があるかどうかは関係ない
whether economic refugees
経済難民かどうか
economic migrants or refugees
経済移民または難民
These different identities
これらの異なるアイデンティティ
In fact, it is impossible to know exactly
実際のところ、正確に知ることは不可能です
and explain a dilemma and experience they encountered
彼らが遭遇したジレンマと経験を説明します
That's why
それが理由です
So we need to compare a
したがって、比較する必要があります
The concept of immigration and this imagination are further investigated
移民の概念とその想像力をさらに探求する
Those few stories help us build a simple context
これらのいくつかのストーリーは、シンプルなコンテキストを構築するのに役立ちます
This is what I was probably just trying to say
これがおそらく私が言いたかったことです
After 2000
2000年以降
because of the tightening of border controls
国境管理が強化されているため
so that also changed the policy
それで方針も変わりました
Also reject North Korean defectors from South Korea
韓国からの脱北者も拒否
So some defectors
それで一部の脱北者は
In fact, through China
実は中国を通じて
maybe to thailand
たぶんタイへ
Then I went back and forth to Europe and the United States
それからヨーロッパとアメリカを行ったり来たりしました
then this brings us to
それから、これは私たちにもたらします
Among the problems of survival and freedom in disasters and politics
災害や政治における生存と自由の問題の中で
It might just be a formal number
正式な数字かもしれない
or outline a state of refugee existence
または難民の現状を概説する
That also reminds us
それは私たちにも思い出させます
The whole is in the rainy environment of East Asia
全体が東アジアの雨の多い環境の中にあります
Whether it's civil war
内戦かどうか
Whether it is the Cold War or not, it is actually a situation that has not completely ended.
冷戦であろうがなかろうが、実は完全には終わっていない状況です。
So after defecting from North Korea, Po Yeon Mi had a saying
北朝鮮から亡命した後、ポ・ヨンミはこう言いました。
He said why he left
彼は去った理由を語った
just want to live like a human
ただ人間らしく生きたいだけ
Then this imagination of wanting to live like a human being
そして、人間らしく生きたいというこの想像力は、
Back to a discussion about human rights
人権に関する議論に戻る
Let us see a couple of very complex paradoxes
非常に複雑なパラドックスをいくつか見てみましょう
For example, where do the human rights of refugees come from?
たとえば、難民の人権はどこから来るのでしょうか？
If we go back to these conventions
これらの慣例に立ち返ると、
stipulated in the convention
条約で定められた
But these provisions of the convention
しかし、この条約の規定は、
Which unit is there to implement, realize and guarantee?
実装、実現、保証する単位はどれですか?
So Hanna two rounds in the 1940s
ハンナは1940年代に2ラウンド
In these notes written in the 1950s
1950年代に書かれたこれらのメモには
In fact, we are constantly discussing this issue about human rights.
実際、私たちはこの人権問題について常に議論しています。
the issue of citizenship
市民権の問題
from his point of view
彼の観点から
without citizenship
市民権なしで
In fact, it is almost equal to no human rights
事実上、それは人権がないのに等しい
Because you don't have a country to provide your human rights protection
人権を守ってくれる国がないから
Human rights are actually the very people who are deprived of human rights
人権とは、実際には人権を剥奪された人々そのものである
the one that was attached
付いていたもの
imagined political rights
想像上の政治的権利
So if we go back to the whole political practice of refugee movement
それでは、難民運動の政治的実践全体に戻ってみると、
It is often seen that a situation like this occurs
このような状況が発生することがよくあります
That is to say, when he has no way to obtain any local acceptance and status
つまり、地元での受け入れや地位を得る手段がない場合です。
These people are excluded
こういう人たちは除外される
Whether it's cast adrift at sea
海に漂流しても
or simply be resisted or shut down in this
あるいは、単に抵抗されるか、この問題でシャットダウンされるだけです
Beyond this so-called barbed wire
このいわゆる有刺鉄線を越えて
So Allen said that this Paradise is
それでアレンは言った、この楽園は
after you lose your human rights
人権を失った後
This makes the issue of human rights a key
このため、人権問題が鍵となる
so what
だから何
how about this from citizen
市民からはどうですか？
through the protection of citizens to make these people
国民の保護を通じて、これらの人々を
have access to the same human rights protections
同じ人権保護を受けることができる
become an important starting point for the entire human rights discussion
人権に関する議論全体の重要な出発点となる
But this is only one end of the human rights debate
しかし、これは人権論争の一端にすぎません
I skip here a little bit
ここで少し飛ばします
come back later
後で戻ってきます
Also recently on the sidelines of the human rights debate
最近では人権議論の傍らでも
Because from another French sociologist
なぜなら、別のフランスの社会学者によると、
From Huang Siye's point of view
ファン・シエの視点から
The idea of ​​talking about human rights
人権について話すという考え
In fact, it is a process of political consultation
実際には、それは政治的協議のプロセスです
It is precisely because these people have no human rights
こういう人たちには人権がないからこそ
But you admit that they are human
でもあなたは彼らが人間であることを認めます
So human rights have become a topic worthy of everyone's concern and discussion
したがって、人権は誰もが懸念し議論する価値のあるテーマとなっています
So that means when we discuss human rights
つまり、私たちが人権について議論するときは、
In fact, we are comparing the human problem with the mobile problem and the refugee problem
実際、私たちは人間の問題をモバイル問題や難民問題と比較しています。
Put it on a political god
政治の神にそれを置く
Here we can directly think of
ここで直接考えられるのは、
For example, think about Hong Kong, which we supported very much a while ago
たとえば、少し前に私たちが非常に支援していた香港について考えてみましょう。
Many Hongkongers want to come and stay
多くの香港人が来て滞在したいと考えています
Whether you can stay or not is actually a lot of questions here.
ここに滞在できるかどうかは、実は多くの疑問があります。
It's not that we verbally
口頭で言っているわけではありません
Conscious support for them
彼らに対する意識的なサポート
we can easily hijack them
私たちは簡単にそれらを乗っ取ることができます
This involves the revision of the presidential decree
これには大統領令の改正が含まれる
to all kinds of national borders and national political imagination
あらゆる種類の国境と国家政治的想像力へ
these topics
これらのトピック
Those things are actually
それらのことは実際には
view throughout the
全体を通して見る
Our current imagination of politics
政治に対する私たちの現在の想像力
above this question
この質問の上に
are very closely related to
～と非常に密接に関係している
So Hong Siye said
そこでホン・シエは言った
There is a saying that is
という諺があります
These refugees fighting for human rights
人権のために戦う難民たち
or wait for human rights
あるいは人権を待っている
Humanitarian Refugees
人道難民
In fact, in the whole social community
実際、社会コミュニティ全体で
no share
シェアなし
It's just that they don't actually have such a share
実際にはそれほどのシェアを持っていないだけです
But what?
でも何？
It is precisely this lack
まさにこの欠如こそが
is that we are worth discussing and working hard
それは、私たちは話し合って一生懸命働く価値があるということです
to make it up
それを補うために
That's also in a sense
それもある意味で
pushes us to imagine
私たちに想像を促す
In the context of Taiwan
台湾の文脈で
to imagine the existence
存在を想像する
or that name
またはその名前
such a
そのような
A possible advance on the law
法律の進歩の可能性
Do we have such a tolerance
私たちにそんな寛容さがあるのか
is there such a one
そんなものはありますか
willing to accept one's own mind
自分の心を受け入れようとする
to receive those who might come into our territory
私たちの領域に来るかもしれない人々を受け入れるため
these refugees
この難民たち
Today we are almost
今日はほぼ
This issue is not discussed in this society
この問題はこの社会では議論されていない
Surprisingly
驚くべきことに
In fact, we also have such a meaning of accepting refugees.
実は難民の受け入れにはそういう意味もあるんです。
If you go back to Peng Hu's story about the Meiying area,
彭胡の美営地区に関する話に戻ると、
then today we will
それでは今日はそうします
what can we do
私たちは何ができる
participate in the international community for these
これらのために国際社会に参加する
People who drift and suffer in the world
世界を漂い、苦しむ人々
Offer some of our possible assistance
私たちが可能な支援を提供します
Where are our formal conditions and our legal conditions
私たちの正式な条件と法的条件はどこにあるのか
This may be our further
これは私たちのさらなる進化かもしれません
worthy of discussion in this society
この社会で議論する価値がある
then time is limited
それなら時間は限られている
I'm going back a little bit quickly to two snippets
少し急いで 2 つのスニペットに戻ります
I especially want to emphasize
特に強調したいのは
Especially in these two segments
特にこれら 2 つのセグメントでは
Wanting to repeat the further misfortune is
更なる不幸を繰り返したいのは
In fact, for refugees
実は難民にとっても
the situation they live in
彼らが置かれている状況
What we can see is
私たちが見ることができるのは、
language and writing
言語と文章
In fact, it is a very important ability
実はとても大切な能力なのです
with the condition
条件付きで
because it's about whether they can be seen
見えるかどうかの問題だから
so many refugee stories
たくさんの難民の話
in a certain sense
ある意味で
Although there is such a book market
こういうブックマーケットがあるのに
These needs for spectacle
スペクタクルに対するこうしたニーズ
but a larger part
しかし、より大きな部分は
record keeping
記録の保存
The experience and experience of these people
この人たちの経験や経験
So that is to say
つまり、
we can't just blame the book market
書籍市場だけを責めることはできない
may want specific marketing
特定のマーケティングが必要な場合がある
For example, a type like Puyanmei
例えばプヤンメイのようなタイプ
image
画像
or put all these
またはこれらをすべて入れてください
The refugee experience has become a
難民の経験は、
Very orientalized story
非常に東洋的な物語
At the same time beyond such a critique
同時に、そのような批判を超えて
we should also see
私たちも見るべきです
behind these stories
これらの物語の背後にある
the moods it wants to record
記録したい気分
follow the sound
音をたどって
Because these sounds may just be
なぜならこれらの音はただのかもしれないから
a possibility that they can be heard
彼らの声が聞こえる可能性
Back to Erlan
エルランに戻る
When Erlan was discussing that there were too many refugees
エルランが難民が多すぎると話し合っていたとき
there is a very
とてもあります
self-deprecating
自虐的な
Or a statement like Synical
シニカルみたいな格言とか
He said what refugees need most
彼は難民が最も必要としているものについて語った
What refugees need most is people's livelihood
難民が最も必要としているのは人々の暮らしです
what kind of livelihood
どのような生計を立てているのか
What kind of livelihood is good
どのような暮らしが良いのか
as long as you can make trouble
迷惑をかけられる限り
able to be seen
見ることができる
then you have a chance for power
そうすればあなたには力を得るチャンスがある
Think about it, everyone
皆さん、考えてみてください
In fact, in our society
実際、私たちの社会では
in today's world
今日の世界では
probably a lot of the time
おそらく多くの場合
those who can't be heard
聞こえない人たち
with those who can't be seen
見えない人たちと
Or the crowd is actually not recognized by us
あるいは、群衆は実際には私たちに認識されていません
remember and understand
覚えて理解する
So so language and story
言語もストーリーもまあまあ
ID, diary, write these things
ID、日記、こんなこと書いて
i think it might be in
入っているかもしれないと思う
researching refugee stories
難民の話を研究する
An action that is particularly worthy of our concern
特に懸念すべき行為
From this point of view
この観点から
all
全て
or in my understanding of
または私の理解では
so-called literary studies
いわゆる文学研究
or cultural studies
または文化研究
It's not just closed doors
ただの密室ではない
Only read novels and stories
小説や物語だけを読む
is a consumer behavior
消費者行動です
It's actually all one
実は全部一つなんです
Our one conduit to the world
私たちの世界への唯一のパイプ
That is to say
つまり
If we have any connection with the world
私たちと世界とのつながりがあれば
What we often have to ask is our connection with the world
私たちがしばしば問いかけなければならないのは、世界と私たちのつながりについてです
where did it come from
それはどこから来たの
Where do we start our relationship with the world?
私たちは世界との関係をどこから始めればよいのでしょうか?
I am borrowing, for example, one from Teacher Qian Yongxiang
たとえば、銭永祥先生から借りています。
i think he has a
彼は1つ持っていると思います
It's an interesting question, he said
興味深い質問ですね、と彼は言いました
Especially when talking about cross-strait relations, he said
特に両岸関係について話すとき、彼はこう言った。
People of their generation may not know
同世代の人は知らないかもしれない
Teacher Qian Yongxiang
銭永祥先生
Also in the Institute
研究所にもあります
A retired professor at this human center
このヒューマンセンターの退職教授
retired researcher then he is this
退職した研究者なら彼はこれだ
contact ideas
連絡先のアイデア
an editor in chief of this publication
この出版物の編集長
He actually cared for so long
彼は本当に長い間気にかけてくれました
The interaction between the two sides of the strait, especially the exchange of ideas
海峡の両側の交流、特にアイデアの交換
So he said that in their generation, he was probably
そこで彼は、彼らの世代ではおそらくそうだっただろうと言いました。
the 50s
50年代
Born in the late 40s and 50s
40年代末50年代出生
This so-called
このいわゆる
people of this generation
この世代の人たち
He said that in their interactions with mainland Chinese people
中国本土の人々との交流の中で、彼はこう語った。
There is this care of a modern China
現代中国にはこんな配慮がある
That is to say, for them, communication between the two sides of the strait
つまり、彼らにとっては海峡の両側間のコミュニケーションです。
Talking about modern China is a common language for each other
現代中国について話すことはお互いの共通言語です
or shared care
または共同ケア
But our generation
でも私たちの世代は
Or the generation later than us
あるいは私たちより後の世代
When communicating with the mainland
本土と通信する場合
what is our connection
私たちのつながりは何ですか
our relationship today
今日の私たちの関係
Probably Rising China, right?
おそらく台頭する中国ですよね？
Maybe it's a Chinese threat or something
もしかしたら中国の脅威か何かかもしれない
So from a conversation like this
さて、こんな会話から
What I'm actually going to expand on is that
私が実際に拡張しようとしているのは、
not the point is not to say
重要なのは言うことではない
Are we already in the world
私たちはすでに世界にいるのか
Or do we lack an international outlook
それとも国際的な視野が欠けているのでしょうか
No further connection to the world etc.
それ以上世界とのつながりはありません。
The point is that
ポイントは、
How do we connect with the world
私たちは世界とどのようにつながるのか
i think the president's reading
社長が読んでると思う
different novels and stories
さまざまな小説や物語
In fact, it provides exactly one
実際、それは正確に 1 つを提供します
a way to bring us into the world
私たちをこの世界に導く方法
I feel special in this
これには特別な気がします
how to say
どのように言って
Thanks to myself for being able to work in such an academic field of literature
このような文学という学問の分野で働ける自分に感謝します
to grow and develop
成長し発展する
because it really drives me some
それは本当に私を駆り立ててくれるから
Opportunities that may not exist in other fields
他の分野では存在しないかもしれないチャンス
And these opportunities are actually some of our different channels to the world.
そして、これらの機会は実際、世界へのさまざまなチャネルの一部です。
So today on this occasion I can share these discussions with you
そこで今日この機会に、これらの議論を皆さんと共有したいと思います
Actually a big expectation
実は大きな期待
In fact, I hope that the friends here
実際、ここにいる友達がそうしてくれることを願っています
In addition to understanding what a researcher's research colleagues are doing
研究者の研究仲間が何をしているかを理解することに加えて、
Also think about the ways in which we can interact with the world
また、世界とどのように関わることができるのかについても考えてみましょう。
What topics and topics are worthy of our development and concern?
私たちの発展と関心に値するトピックやトピックは何ですか?
From this we can reconstruct
これから再構成できます
even develop a Taiwan society that is different from the past
過去とは異なる台湾社会を発展させることさえ
and the relationship between Taiwanese society and the world
そして台湾社会と世界との関係
Then I think it's almost time to talk about this place today
それでは、そろそろ今日はこの場所について話してもいい頃だと思います
If you say something bad, please include more
悪いことを言ったらもっと詳しく書いてください
Thank you very much Vice President Huang and
黄副社長、誠にありがとうございました。
Dean Wang Qin's family members and friends present
王秦学部長の家族と友人のプレゼント
very happy to have this opportunity today
今日はこのような機会を頂けてとても嬉しいです
I can meet you here
ここで会えます
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
this we thank you for this
これには感謝しています
Professor Wang's explanation of this
これについての王教授の説明
Real Refugees and Refugees Presented in Literature
文学で表現される現実の難民と難民
The relationship between the two is of course very complicated
もちろん二人の関係は非常に複雑です
There are thousands of threads in this intricate relationship
この複雑な関係には何千もの糸が存在します
I think everyone must have different questions in their minds.
きっと誰もが心の中にさまざまな疑問を抱いているはずです。
want to ask questions
質問したい
So I think we're going to open it up to the audience right now.
それで、今から観客に公開しようと思います。
to ask questions
質問すること
then we have a good one
それなら良いものがあるよ
Do you want to explain the small gift?
ささやかな贈り物について説明したいですか？
We have a quota of 10 small gifts
小さなギフトには10​​個の割り当てがあります
That's an alcohol bottle, although the epidemic has slowed down
あれはアルコールボトルだ、流行は落ち着いたが
But this may take a while so we'll
ただし、これには時間がかかる可能性があるため、
Give everyone a souvenir made by Academia Sinica
中央研究院が作ったお土産をみんなにプレゼント
Thanks
ありがとう
yes
はい
now please everyone
さあ、皆さんお願いします
speak up
声を上げて
Hold your hand, this gentleman raises his hand first
手を握ってください、この紳士が先に手を挙げます
Please say
言ってください
Send the day first
最初にその日を送信します
then come join the army just aired
それなら、放送されたばかりの軍隊に来てください
i see them
私は彼らを見ます
At the beginning they also knew that there was a shortage
彼らも最初は不足があることを知っていました
Medicine, in March last year
医学、昨年3月
full drug shortage
完全な麻薬不足
food
食べ物
That's when they were all pitiful
その時はみんな可哀想だった
The east belt lacks everything
東のベルトには何も欠けている
In the end, the Taiwan government was always missing, and they didn't forget about us.
結局、台湾政府はいつも行方不明でしたが、私たちのことを忘れていませんでした。
In this way, after joining the army, give me the Taiwan flag
こうして入隊したら台湾の国旗をください
I think
私が思うに
impossible
不可能的
Would you like to stand in the middle
真ん中に立ってみませんか
Because you are the protagonist under this brow light
この眉の光の下ではあなたが主役だから
Thank you very much for sharing this friend
この友人を共有してくれてありがとう
Indeed, I think we are actually on this matter in Ukraine
実際、私たちはウクライナで実際にこの問題に取り組んでいると思います
But it should be said
しかし、それは言うべきです
I think Taiwanese society has
台湾社会はこうなっていると思います。
This desire and imagination for participation in the international community
国際社会への参加に対するこの願望と想像力
desire, will and ability
願望、意志、能力
In fact, it is much stronger than before
実際、以前よりもはるかに強力になっています
Glad to be there to actually visit
実際に訪問できてよかったです
See this friend who Naiming helped
Naiming が助けてくれたこの友人を見てください
I probably think
たぶん思う
if stretched a bit
少し伸びたら
What I'm trying to say is probably
私が言いたいのは、おそらく
Our Contact with Naiming
ナイミングとの連絡
Including myself, I didn't actually have any real contact with Naiming.
私も含めて、実はナイミンとは実際に何の接点もありませんでした。
so i can't say
だから言えない
what should we say
何と言えばいいでしょうか
But from the context of a literary study
しかし、文学研究の文脈から見ると、
In fact, what keeps reminding ourselves is an ethical issue
実際、常に自分たちに思い出させているのは倫理的な問題です
That is, in the context of this contact
つまり、この連絡の文脈では、
what was their response
彼らの反応は何でしたか
what is our attitude
私たちの態度は何ですか
And are there any other expectations that interfere with this relationship?
そして、この関係を妨げる他の期待はありますか？
In fact, it may be a very simple relationship of mutual assistance and assistance.
実はそれは、とてもシンプルな助け合い・助け合いの関係なのかもしれません。
Then when I understand that means
それからそれが意味すると理解すると、
A lot of international aid today is in the context of Taiwan
現在の国際援助の多くは台湾に関連したものである
There is such a need to see Taiwan or the expectation of Taiwan Can help
台湾を見る必要性、または台湾への期待が役に立ちます
Then I think it's understandable, and it's what we've been doing for so many years.
それなら当然だと思いますし、それが私たちが長年やってきたことなのです。
The accumulated political, cultural, and economic power
蓄積された政治的、文化的、経済的な力
An opportunity worthy of international exposure
国際的に知られる価値のある機会
But what I keep thinking about is probably
でも、私が考え続けているのは、おそらく
Then, are there some ethical issues that may be deeper in this, and we will think about it later?
では、これにはさらに深い倫理的な問題があるのでしょうか。それについては後ほど考えます。
Then I just throw this question out for everyone
それでは、この質問を皆さんに投げかけます
and no further criticisms or thoughts on this
これについてはこれ以上の批判や意見はありません
I also hope to take this opportunity to hear more about your experiences and ideas.
また、この機会に皆様の経験やアイデアについて詳しくお聞きできれば幸いです。
That's because our central research
それは私たちの中心的な研究だからです
Because Ukraine has accepted many Ukrainian refugees since the war
ウクライナは戦後多くのウクライナ難民を受け入れてきたから
Not to mention some compatriots from Hong Kong like this
このような香港の同胞もいるのは言うまでもありません
So this is a process where you can see a lot of hard work.
つまり、これは多くの努力が見られるプロセスです。
Well, we're actually lucky too.
そうですね、私たちも実は幸運です。
This hope does not become a refugee
この希望は難民にならない
that other
そのほかの
This woman is fine, let's start with a woman
この女性は大丈夫です、まずは女性から始めましょう
one man one woman one man one woman
一男一女一男一女
Hello teacher, I am a student of the Institute of Literature
こんにちは、先生、私は文学部の学生です。
is also a nonfiction writer
ノンフィクション作家でもある
Then I focus on the topic of "Tibetans in Exile"
次に「亡命チベット人」の話題に焦点を当てます。
Then I just heard the teacher say
それから私はちょうど先生がこう言うのを聞きました
Do you think language and writing are very important
言語と文章はとても重要だと思いますか
because need to be seen
見られる必要があるから
I agree with this
これに同意する
Well, I have a small question,
さて、ちょっとした質問なのですが、
Because the "Exile" we are in contact with
なぜなら、私たちが接触しているのは「追放者」だからです。
In the process of telling the story, in fact
実際、物語を語る過程で、
found out that one thing is
あることが分かりました
In fact, the so-called traumatic memory
実は、いわゆるトラウマ的記憶というのは、
They are likely to be in the present moment of memory preservation
彼らは記憶を保存している現在の瞬間にいる可能性が高い
because it hurts
痛いから
So they have to do the preservation in a twisted way
したがって、彼らは歪んだ方法で保存を行わなければなりません
which is very likely what we recorded
それは私たちが録音したものである可能性が非常に高いです
the story we heard was
私たちが聞いた話は
There will be this truth of truth and falsity of the story
物語には真実と偽りが存在するだろう
that being a writer is because a recorder
作家であることは記録者であるからである
what do you think teacher
先生はどう思いますか
but we have to write we have to say
しかし、私たちは書かなければなりません、私たちは言わなければなりません
But I really have no way to verify the authenticity of the story
しかし、その話の信憑性を確認する方法はまったくありません
thank you very much for your question
ご質問いただきありがとうございます
It's really common
本当によくあることです
A common discussion on refugee issues
難民問題に関する共通の議論
For example, when a
たとえば、
How about this refugee seeking asylum?
庇護を求めているこの難民はどうですか？
The story he told, how do you verify that what he said is true?
彼が語った話、彼が言ったことが真実であることをどのように検証しますか?
It's fake, it's included in the novel I just described
それは偽物です、先ほど説明した小説に含まれています
In fact, there is one, the third book
実は、3冊目の本があります。
In fact, there is a very important plot is
実は、非常に重要なプロットがあります。
He this Loki One when he came out
彼はロキ・ワンが出てきたとき
In fact, no, I don't have any documents on me anymore.
実際、いいえ、もう手元に書類はありません。
can prove who he is
彼が誰であるかを証明できる
So he needs a third party to help him
したがって、彼には助けてくれる第三者が必要です
the process of doing a test or piece together a story
テストを行ったり、ストーリーを組み立てたりするプロセス
Therefore, in the process
したがって、その過程で
delayed the time he was able to obtain detention
彼が拘留を得ることができる時間を遅らせた
So the question you raised is a very crucial one.
したがって、あなたが提起した質問は非常に重要です。
one question but
一つ質問ですが、
Then this key issue will be in the field of practice
そうすれば、この重要な問題は実践の分野で行われることになります
Formation is sometimes a form for refugees
フォーメーションは難民のための形式であることもある
Further make things difficult for example
たとえば、物事をさらに困難にする
Ask him to keep repeating the things he went through
彼が経験したことを繰り返し続けるように頼みます
It can be a very painful experience for him
それは彼にとってとても辛い経験になるかもしれない
or
また
the truth of what he said
彼の言ったことの真実
make him helpless
彼を無力にする
make him feel that he is not only not accepted
自分は受け入れられていないだけではないと彼に感じさせる
Even being further questioned and suspected
さらに尋問され、疑われても
Then this may all be at the same scene
そうすると、これはすべて同じ場面にある可能性があります
A key issue in ethics
倫理における重要な問題
But another level of problem
しかし、別のレベルの問題
is in this part of the story
物語のこの部分にあります
Then this involves the process of writing the story.
次に、これには物語を書くプロセスが含まれます。
it is a collaboration
それはコラボレーションです
For example, his narration was written down by another person
たとえば、彼のナレーションは別の人によって書き取られたものです
Or he worked hard in his own way
それとも彼なりに頑張ったのか
talk about his experience
彼の経験について話す
But it may not be able to make everyone understand
でも、すべての人に理解してもらうことはできないかもしれない
Or in other words, there are many of these
というかそういうのが多い
very strange thing
とても奇妙なこと
let me give you an example
例をあげましょう
In this Campo-Le
このカンポ・レでは
It is the refugee experience in Cambodia
カンボジアでの難民体験です
There is a saying that
という諺があります
One of the sayings circulating as this refugee experience is that
この難民体験として広まっている格言の一つに、次のようなものがあります。
You have to plant a tree
木を植えなければなりません
It has a saying that is
という格言があります
you need to
必要がある
planted like a tree
木のように植えられた
That statement is incomprehensible to most people.
その発言はほとんどの人には理解できない。
People in the veins will find it strange
静脈にいる人はそれを奇妙に思うでしょう
what is like a tree
木に似ているものは何ですか
So the explanation of these advances is that
したがって、これらの進歩について説明すると、
The reason to be like a tree
木のようになる理由
it's because we're going to keep silent
それは私たちが黙っているからです
we will continue to grow
私たちは成長し続けます
But let's not touch the others
でも他のものには触れないようにしましょう
Don't let our language oppress us
私たちの言語で私たちを抑圧しないでください
Because during the process of fleeing in Cambodia,
なぜなら、カンボジアで逃亡する過程で、
Probably because of this, of course there are a lot of details
おそらくこれのせいで、もちろん詳細はたくさんあります
I can't speak very clearly and clearly now.
今はあまりはっきりとはっきりと話すことができません。
but in simple terms
しかし、簡単に言えば
If we plant this into a tree
これを木に植えたら
If it is a metaphor for the escape experience
逃亡体験の比喩なら
In fact, the ability to read these metaphors when we need them
実際、必要なときにこれらの比喩を読み取る能力は、
Then this ability involves saying
そして、この能力には次のことが含まれます
How do we contextualize the place where these metaphors take place
これらの比喩が行われる場所をどのように文脈化するか
How to provide the context of this pair of metaphors
このペアの比喩のコンテキストを提供する方法
How to understand the context of these metaphors
これらの比喩の文脈を理解する方法
in the course of history
歴史の流れの中で
The meaning in this historical context
この歴史的文脈における意味
Then I think the most important possibility
それから私が考える最も重要な可能性は
Back to the question of authenticity
信憑性の問題に戻る
The fact is that we should not simply doubt
事実は、単に疑うべきではないということです
should say so
そう言うべきだ
Let's not be too obsessed with judgments of authenticity
真贋の判断にこだわりすぎないようにしましょう
because as an outsider
なぜなら部外者として
In fact, it is difficult for you to judge the authenticity
実際のところ、真贋を判断するのは難しい
Right, if you're not the party
そう、あなたが当事者ではないとしても
if you haven't experienced
経験していない場合
If you have no other supporting materials
他にサポート資料がない場合
I'm afraid it's hard for you to judge
あなたが判断するのは難しいと思います
Is this story true or false?
この話は本当ですか、それとも嘘ですか?
or in this story
あるいはこの物語の中で
is there any exaggeration
誇張はありますか
But what we want to hear is
しかし、私たちが聞きたいのは、
Or what we're going to read is in
あるいは、私たちがこれから読むものは、
something beyond these rhetoric
これらのレトリックを超えた何か
It doesn't matter if it's his heart
それが彼の心だとしても関係ない
Whether it's his trauma
それが彼のトラウマなのか
Whether it's some clues he wants to leave behind
それは彼が残したい手がかりなのかどうか
I think this is as a
これは次のとおりだと思います
I think where we should pay attention
どこに注目すべきかと思います
instead of saying
言う代わりに
Because there's probably some exaggerated material here
おそらく誇張された内容が含まれている可能性があるため、
So he cannot be further adopted
したがって、彼はさらに養子縁組されることはできません
what i want to say is
私が言いたいのは
so i care
だから私は気にします
stories about refugees
難民についての話
Actually, I just had a slideshow that didn't say anything in particular.
実は、特に何も言わずにスライドショーを見せていただけでした。
That is, it is often a so-called future-tive history
つまり、それは多くの場合、いわゆる未来志向の歴史です。
or future-tive documentation
または将来のドキュメント
The records of these stories are actually very fragmented.
これらの物語の記録は実際には非常に断片的です。
It's all accidental in its retention
その保持はすべて偶然です
So we actually need a lot of effort
したがって、実際には多くの努力が必要です
To piece together these fragmentary and incomplete ingredients
断片的で不完全な材料をつなぎ合わせて
And here we must run the risk of facing the real embarrassment
そしてここで私たちは本当の当惑に直面する危険を冒さなければなりません
So my advice would be to try to stay out of its sight
したがって、私のアドバイスは、その視界から遠ざかるよう努めることです
trying to read between the lines
行間を読もうとしている
Rather than just grasping the so-called truth
いわゆる真実を把握するだけではなく
this is my simple answer
これが私の単純な答えです
ok sir
わかりました、先生
Hello teacher, this thank you very wonderful
こんにちは、先生、本当にありがとうございます
And very, very responsible speeches
そしてとてもとても責任あるスピーチ
Usually in speeches I think of an issue like race in America
私は通常、スピーチではアメリカの人種のような問題について考えます
just like black people
黒人と同じように
They played the role of black slaves to Delamin
彼らはデラミンに対して黒人奴隷の役割を果たした
So they're sort of a refugee.
つまり彼らは一種の難民なのです。
They also spent a lot of effort to fight for freedom.
彼らはまた、自由のために戦うために多大な努力を費やしました。
Then just know the racial inequality of black people now
それなら今すぐ黒人の人種的不平等を知りましょう
Or socioeconomic inequality is still a very, very big problem
あるいは、社会経済的不平等は依然として非常に大きな問題である
So I want to ask the teacher if
そこで先生に聞きたいのですが、
This is actually quite
これは実際にはかなりです
quite
とても
I think it's pretty
きれいだと思います
don't know how to solve
解決方法がわかりません
That is, what kind of resettlement will refugees have in their new countries?
つまり、難民は新しい国でどのような第三国定住をすることになるのでしょうか？
how to make them follow
彼らをフォローさせる方法
how to make them better
それらをより良くする方法
Do you have any opinions or indirect shares from the young teachers?
若い先生方からの意見や間接的な共有はありますか？
ok thank you very much for this question
わかりました、ご質問ありがとうございます
I'm afraid it's a bit beyond my ability
申し訳ありませんが、それは私の能力を少し超えています
Sounds like such a huge mission to save Kasen
歌仙を救うというのはとても大きな使命のようですね
But I think it's fair to say that
しかし、そう言っても当然だと思います
racial issues
人種問題
Actually in this refugee story that I was trying to describe
実は私が描こうとしていたこの難民の物語の中で
In fact, there is a side
実は一面もある
is the difference of identity
アイデンティティの違いです
This difference in identity may be racial
このアイデンティティの違いは人種によるものかもしれません
probably an accent
おそらくアクセント
Maybe even today is a regional
たぶん今日でも地域的なものです
So it is not surprising that there are various differences in human society
ですから、人間社会にさまざまな違いがあっても不思議ではありません。
But the way we treat differences
しかし、違いをどう扱うかというと、
But it often adopts a method of exclusion and violence
しかし、それはしばしば排除と暴力の方法を採用します
then this will be
そうすればこれはこうなります
This should be our human society
これが私たちの人間社会であるべきです
A question that should be constantly reflected on
常に反省すべき問い
So back to that question about black people
さて、黒人についての質問に戻りますが、
Or this question from ethnic minorities
あるいは少数民族からのこの質問
including the question of placement
配置の問題も含めて
Here I think there are two aspects worth considering
ここで、考慮に値する 2 つの側面があると思います
the first is
一つ目は
Talk about the problem of placement
配置の問題について話す
In fact, there is an angle to say
実はこう言う角度もあります
how do we bring him in
どうやって彼を連れて行こうか
So we, for example, through various
そこで私たちは、例えばさまざまな取り組みを通じて、
Funding e.g. speaking language courses
語学コースなどの資金調達
send them to language courses
語学コースに通わせる
so that they can quickly integrate into the society
彼らが早く社会に溶け込めるように
So in this sense
ですから、そういう意味では
We are expecting these names to be us
私たちはこれらの名前が私たちであることを期待しています
OK
OK
Then you should think about it
それなら考えてみればいいよ
We expect others to be us
私たちは他人が自分であることを期待します
it sounds like nothing is wrong
何も問題がないように聞こえます
right
右
Do you think this is not possible? Shouldn’t it be?
そんなことは不可能だと思いますか?そうすべきではないでしょうか?
It doesn't sound like anything is wrong, does it?
何も問題はないようですね。
Since you came to our country, you should
私たちの国に来たからには、そうすべきです
when you're in Rome do what Romans do
ローマにいるときはローマ人と同じことをしてください
When you come to Rome, you have to learn how the Romans live
ローマに来たら、ローマ人の暮らし方を学ばなければなりません
But for Naming
でもネーミングに関しては
His coming may not be what he wants to come
彼の来日は彼が望んでいることではないかもしれない
He was accidentally
彼は偶然だった
Or because of these accidents that he couldn't resist
あるいは、彼が抵抗できなかったこれらの事故のせいで
and came to this place
そしてこの場所に来ました
then one
それから 1 つ
Police have a lot of help
警察は多くの協力を得ています
But such a request or expectation
でもそんな要望や期待は
he became what we imagined
彼は私たちが想像していたものになった
good no missiles
ミサイルは無いから良いよ
Then the well-behaved and kind Nai Ming
それから行儀が良くて優しいナミン
Even Nai Min, who is very grateful
ナイミンもとても感謝しています
In fact, it is a big burden for him.
実際、それは彼にとって大きな負担だ。
So in the Naming study
そこで、ネーミングの研究では
It should be said that in the critique of Naming studies
ネーミング研究の批評においてはこう言われるべきである。
there is a big discussion
大きな議論があります
In fact, for this debt
実はこの借金に関しては
It's just that Nai Ming has a feeling of apology
ナイミンには申し訳ない気持ちがあるだけだ
This discussion because this debt reflects the
この負債が反映されているため、この議論は
His freedom was actually given
彼に自由は実際に与えられた
His freedom is not what he fought for
彼の自由は彼が戦って得たものではない
but because of these various external factors
しかし、これらのさまざまな外部要因のせいで
gave him such a free opportunity
彼にそのような自由な機会を与えた
So he should survive
だから彼は生き残るべきだ
This seems to be in line with our general social logic
これは私たちの一般的な社会的論理と一致しているようです
such an idea
そのような考え
But when you go back to the refugee experience and history
しかし、難民の経験と歴史に立ち返ると、
In the context of movement
動きの文脈において
you'll find that for them
あなたは彼らのためにそれを見つけるでしょう
That's actually a bigger burden
むしろそのほうが負担が大きい
As a result, we encounter many so-called
その結果、私たちは多くのいわゆる
This so-called immigrant group
このいわゆる移民グループは、
In fact, in the end, they are all regarded as people in this society.
実際、彼らは結局のところ、この社会の人間としてみなされています。
problem group
問題グループ
But that problem is like what we have today
しかし、その問題は今日私たちが抱えているものと似ています
Facing the child in exile
亡命中の子供と向き合う
so-called problem children
いわゆる問題児
Maybe that's not the problem with these kids and children
たぶんそれはこの子供たちの問題ではない
It is the society that treats these children
この子供たちを扱うのは社会です
with the child
子供たちと
face to face
面と向かって
The expectations and requirements for them
彼らに対する期待と要件
perhaps far beyond
おそらくはるかに超えた
their burden
彼らの負担
then this is what i think
それならこれが私が思うことです
How to understand refugees
難民をどう理解するか
between the receiving country
受け入れ国との間で
Acceptance of a complex relationship between societies
社会間の複雑な関係の受け入れ
an ethical dimension
倫理的な側面
Then of course race is a thing I think
それから、もちろん人種も私が考えることです
The very core question here
ここでの非常に核心的な質問
why are they required
なぜそれらが必要なのか
because they're not like us
彼らは私たちとは違うから
so
それで
to eat pork like us
私たちと同じように豚肉を食べる
come here to do something like us
私たちのように何かをするためにここに来てください
Well this is actually
まあこれは実際のところ
We don't see the context of their life
彼らの人生の背景が見えない
What exactly is it
正確には何ですか
So I think treating the other back to Derrida this time I just
だから、今度は相手をデリダに戻すと思います。
Sorry for not being able to
できなくてごめんなさい
expanded part
拡張部分
When Derrida talked about Vietnam and Namibia
デリダがベトナムとナミビアについて語ったとき
he was talking about a
彼はあることについて話していました
is an unconditional Vietnamese
無条件のベトナム人です
It's that you can't ask him to do what he is
それは、あなたが彼に何をすべきかを尋ねることはできないということです。
You have to take it as it is
ありのままに受け取らなければなりません
he is like that
彼はそのような人です
and accept him that way
そしてそのように彼を受け入れてください
so you can expand a
を拡張できます
Comparing the above relationship with ethical significance
上記の関係と倫理的意義の比較
otherwise
さもないと
will always be in a so-called
常にいわゆる状態になります
This humanity gives and
この人間性が与えてくれるのは、
In this expected exchange relationship with this harmonious society
この調和社会との期待される交流関係の中で
This is probably what I learned from reading refugee stories
これは私が難民の物語を読んで学んだことかもしれません
critical refugee studies
重要な難民研究
One of the more important inspirations
最も重要なインスピレーションの 1 つ
share with everyone
みんなと共有する
Please say
言ってください
yes
はい
I am a family member
私は家族の一員です
The family of Wang Shijie
王世傑の家族
I study economics and AI
経済とAIを勉強しています
To that Microsoft today
今日はあのマイクロソフトへ
To learn some advanced OpenAI
高度な OpenAI を学ぶには
i mean now
私が今、意図しているのは
I heard the refugee story
難民の話を聞きました
that
それか
Professor Wang gave me a lot
王先生は私にたくさんのものをくれました
Very
非常
deep impression
深い印象
But I want to ask a question is this
でも質問したいのはこれです
Because I am Tzu Chi
私は慈済だから
Some of us are brothers to help
私たちの中には助けてくれる兄弟もいます
and
と
that
それか
about Ukraine
ウクライナについて
We are also going to pack
梱包もさせていただきます
to donate
寄付する
then we are in
それから私たちはいます
Syria also has
シリアにもある
that is
あれは
We have a lot of seniors who have deep feelings over there.
向こうには思い入れの深い先輩たちがたくさんいます。
this kind
この種
that
それか
to feel
感じる
I mean
つまり
Professor Wang, do you want to say
王教授、言いたいことはありますか？
to experience
体験する
go over there to see
あそこに行って見てください
It's as if I followed my resignation hospital
まるで退職した病院の後を追いかけたようだ
that one a while ago
さっきのあれ
The dean of nursing told me
看護部長が私に言いました
say you
あなたが言います
Like we resigned people is not to
私たちと同じように、人々は辞めるべきではありません
Go to the hospital to feel the patients
病院に行って患者の気持ちを感じよう
Feel it, feel it, there is a question later
感じて、感じて、そして質問が生まれる
I can extend my academic problems later because I study economics
私は経済学を勉強しているので、学業上の問題を後から拡張することができます
This is
これは
Just like you are all academic
皆さんが学者であるのと同じように、
But I've been slowly getting closer to that
でも、少しずつそれに近づいてきました
There are only two parts to the food.
食べ物には2つの部分しかありません。
Talking about life and doing it
人生について話し、それを実践する
Remember all living beings and save all living beings
すべての生きとし生けるものを覚え、すべての生きとし生けるものを救う
Then I mean, the next question comes, that is,
つまり、次の質問は次のとおりです。
Have you ever thought about the development of the aftermath?
その後の展開について考えたことはありますか？
Refugees can become independent
難民は自立できる
because some refugees
難民もいるから
He is a high intellectual like those in Ukraine
彼はウクライナの人々と同じような高等知識人だ
They are capable only because they are refugees
難民だからこそできることがある
I don't want to be burdened by others
他人に負担をかけたくない
so he is creative
だから彼は創造的だ
So we want to follow up
そこでフォローアップしていきたいと思います
is to train him to be useful
彼を役に立つように訓練することだ
So some of the latter we are
後者の一部は私たちです
in tzu chi
子チーで
they are at school
彼らは学校にいます
then educate the child
それから子供を教育する
Then to derive from there is to say
そこから導き出されるのは、次のようになります
Dead refugees don't do harm to another country
難民の死は他国に害を及ぼさない
Accepting a burden is a burden
重荷を受け入れることは重荷である
but be creative
しかし創造的でありなさい
and productive
そして生産的な
but also to promote their economic development
経済発展を促進するためでもあります
Professor Wang, do you want to say that you want to experience it?
王先生、体験してみたいと思いますか？
grateful
ありがたい
Thank you very much Mr. Li for this suggestion
リーさん、この提案をありがとうございました
this i think
これは私が思う
OK, the vice president is here.
はい、副大統領が来ました。
Research institutes can also host groups
研究機関はグループを主催することもできます
In fact, I think for researchers
実際、研究者にとっては
it will be a very useful experience
とても役に立つ経験になるでしょう
and then it will be a very real experience
そうすればそれはとても現実的な経験になるでしょう
Then I myself am mainly in literature
それから私自身は主に文学に携わっています
so i never had such a chance
だからそんなチャンスはなかった
but if any
しかし、もしあれば
I will also be willing to contact and try
私も連絡して試してみます
That's about what I'm going to say
私が言いたいのはそれくらいです
That is to say experience and contact
つまり経験と触れ合い
and long-term relationship
そして長期的な関係
with refugees in our society
私たちの社会の難民たちとともに
or ethnic minorities or immigrants
あるいは少数民族や移民
There will be some context here
ここにはいくつかのコンテキストがあります
or the difference in state
または状態の違い
For example, if I go one day, two days, three days
例えば、1日、2日、3日行ったら
a week a month
月に一週間
There are some very substantial differences here
ここには非常に大きな違いがいくつかあります
Let's say we have this
これがあるとしましょう
friends who have been to refugee camps
難民キャンプに行ったことのある友達
So when you go for a long time
なので、長く行くときは
You're numb to those stories
あなたはそれらの話には無感覚です
You'll cry at first
最初は泣くでしょうね
then you feel
そうしたらあなたは感じます
here we go again
ああ、またか
ok
Ok
then this is what i want
それならこれが私が欲しいものです
just say
言うだけ
Well
良い
this is not to say
これは言うことではありません
it's not an excuse not to go
それは行かない言い訳にはならない
i didn't mean that
そんなつもりじゃなかった
that is
あれは
head this here
ここに向かいます
The specific context may be very important to our experience
特定のコンテキストは私たちの経験にとって非常に重要である可能性があります
an important factor
重要な要素
ok
Ok
so uh
それで、ええと
so of course i
だからもちろん私は
support also uh
サポートもええ
willing to assist these
これらを喜んで支援します
various access and
様々なアクセスや
uh auxiliary
ああ、補助
but i think uh
でも私はああ思う
from a research point of view
研究の観点から
we'll have to think about it
私たちはそれについて考えなければなりません
We are in this process when
私たちがこのプロセスにいるとき、
how did this process happen
このプロセスはどのようにして起こったのか
and in the process
そしてその過程で
what is our status
私たちのステータスは何ですか
this is an uprising
これは反乱です
The rest is what you just mentioned
残りはあなたが今言ったことです
These are all kinds of auxiliary methods.
これらはあらゆる種類の補助的な方法です。
Well, of course I would agree
まあ、もちろん同意します
If they can be productive and so on
生産性を高めることができるかどうかなど
all good of course
もちろん大丈夫です
but this
しかしこれは
it's just us
それは私たちだけです
uh mainstream discourse
ああ、主流の言説
what you have been expecting and imagining
あなたが期待し想像してきたこと
then this is also
それならこれも
uh i think we're talking about these few today
ああ、今日はこれらのいくつかについて話していると思います
or weak one-by-one problems
または個別の問題が弱い
often difficult to overcome
克服するのが難しいことが多い
The mainstream imagination is very clear and clear
主流の想像力は非常に明確で明確です
and even have a high moral basis
そして高い道徳的基盤さえ持っています
think you see we've helped you so much
私たちがあなたをとても助けてきたことがわかると思います
why don't you do it
なぜそれをしないのですか
Then from the context of literature
次に文学の文脈から
What I'm trying to do is a
私がやろうとしているのは、
A certain kind of experience that destroys others as much as possible
他者を可能な限り破壊するある種の経験
Can't say I'm totally capable of being the other
自分が完全に他人になることができるとは言えない
But a certain experience and attempt to destroy the other
しかし、ある経験と他のものを破壊しようとする試み
may be what we want to provide to the society
それが私たちが社会に提供したいものなのかもしれません
Some other thoughts outside of mainstream voices
主流の声以外のその他の考え
I don't think this is necessarily a Hange situation.
これは必ずしもハンジの状況ではないと思います。
It may just be an expansion or an addition
ただの拡張か追加かもしれない
But looking back, I feel that facing the refugee issue today
しかし、振り返ってみると、今日難民問題に直面しているのは、
Often people say that in Europe they say
ヨーロッパではよくこう言われます。
This is called humanitarian crisis
これを人道危機と呼ぶ
humanitarian crisis
人道危機
But the problem is that there is a crisis, not humanity, right?
でも問題は人類ではなく危機があるということですよね？
These refugees aren't a crisis in themselves, are they?
これらの難民自体は危機ではありませんね。
cause refugees
難民を引き起こす
The events of the crisis are actually the agents of the crisis
危機の出来事は実際には危機の媒介である
Right, so back to the definition of a refugee?
そうですね、難民の定義に戻りますか？
Refugees are those who cannot return home, or cannot return home
難民とは故郷に帰れない人、または帰れない人のこと
So if we create a condition today where they can go home
だから今日、彼らが家に帰れる環境を作れば
Is that the real solution to the refugee problem?
それが難民問題の本当の解決策なのでしょうか？
The question is, can we create such conditions?
問題は、そのような状況を作り出すことができるかということです。
Then I think this is not just a face
そうすると、これは顔だけじゃないと思うんです
A state in which you want to solve a problem that has come before you
目の前にある問題を解決したいと思っている状態
but go one step further and go back
でも一歩進んで戻ってみる
What is the premise of reflecting on the whole construction problem
建設問題全体を振り返る前提は何ですか
That's what I think we hope to provide to the society
それが私たちが社会に提供したいことだと考えています
not just go
ただ行くだけではなく
How to say, use the method of posting OK to solve a problem that has already
なんと言うか、OKを貼り付ける方法を使って既存の問題を解決する
Imminent problem Instead, put this imminent problem
差し迫った問題 代わりに、この差し迫った問題を入れてください
While solving the problem, we also think a little bit more deeply.
問題を解決しながら、もう少し深く考えてみます。
See if it can be accessed from the root, or from a relatively large structure
ルートから、または比較的大きな構造からアクセスできるかどうかを確認します。
to reimagine and understand the problem
問題を再考して理解する
Maybe we'll get some different answers
もしかしたら違う答えが得られるかも知れません
this female friend
この女友達
Maintain one man, one woman, one woman, one man
維持一男一女一女一男
so
それで
Hello Professor Wang
こんにちは、王教授
I'm Shi Jiacheng
私は石家成です
I am a
私は
It's like a background engineer doing international aid
国際援助を行うバックグラウンドエンジニアのようなものです
just the staff
スタッフだけ
i feel like i just
私はただのような気がします
I feel very grateful for today's speech
今日のスピーチにはとても感謝しています
Then
それから
I think I may have missed some information just now
今のところ情報を見逃している可能性があると思います
that is
あれは
Professor Wang just mentioned
王教授が先ほど言及した
in literature
文学で
that is
あれは
of these stories
これらの物語の
That's what I just heard a keyword
それが今聞いたキーワードです
is to tell these stories
これらの物語を伝えることです
Maybe he was consumed
もしかしたら彼は消費されてしまったのかもしれない
or being
または存在する
is that there may be a need for a standard
基準が必要かもしれないということです
It's the story of a refugee
難民の物語です
or
また
just mentioned some
いくつか言及したばかりです
some different sketches
いくつかの異なるスケッチ
such a picture of
そんな写真
But I still don't quite understand
でもまだよく分かりません
These
これらは
literary
文学的な
experience with this refugee
この難民との経験
Except for the eligibility of this refugee
この難民の資格を除いて
how to be identified
どのように識別されるか
for their freedom and dignity
彼らの自由と尊厳のために
do you think this has any relationship
これには何か関係があると思いますか
yes this is the first question
はい、これが最初の質問です
Then the second question is to say
次に 2 番目の質問は次のようになります。
because from the food
なぜなら食べ物から
If we look at it from the point of view of food
食の観点から見てみると
that is
あれは
current refugee problem
現在の難民問題
A more modern refugee problem
より現代的な難民問題
maybe like climate refugees
気候難民のようなものかもしれない
caused these crises in the mediterranean
地中海でこれらの危機を引き起こした
Then
それから
not a crisis
危機ではない
that is
あれは
It's Shah
シャーだよ
Northern Sahara
北サハラ
Anyway it is
とにかくそうです
Some of Africa's climate refugees
アフリカの気候難民の一部
is to Europe
ヨーロッパへです
then the crisis in syria
それからシリア危機
and then
その後
like yemen
イエメンのように
or some longer-term issues
または長期的な問題
Or maybe even like the earthquake in Türkiye
あるいは、トゥルキエの地震のようなものかもしれない
Then something like this happens
するとこんな事が起こる
you just mentioned
あなたは今言いました
In fact, most of them are low-to-medium
実際、それらのほとんどは低から中程度です。
Developing countries host the most refugees
発展途上国が最も多くの難民を受け入れている
I can understand that
それは理解できます
literature just can take a while
文学には時間がかかることがある
just might be
ただそうかもしれない
These are the ones integrated into the society
これらは社会に組み込まれているものです
created by descendants of refugees
難民の子孫が作った
But what I want to understand is to say
しかし、私が理解したいのは、
Are you doing this research for
この研究は何のためにやっているのですか？
some of the current refugees
現在の難民の一部
Event is what kind of thought?
イベントとはどのような考えですか？
Thanks
ありがとう
very happy
とても幸せです
There are many friends from the food industry here today
今日は食品業界の友人がたくさん来ています
so i was a little surprised
だからちょっとびっくりした
but also very happy
でもとても幸せです
Because obviously we're in this society
明らかに私たちはこの社会にいるから
There's a lot actually on this subject
この件については実際にはたくさんあります
have many devoted friends
献身的な友人がたくさんいる
Then I think two questions
それから私は2つの質問を考えます
Simply put
簡単に言えば
The previous question was about the story itself
前の質問はストーリー自体に関するものでした
how about these stories
これらの話はどうですか
some of these stories
これらの物語のいくつか
what should i say
私は何を言えばいい
its typicality or its exemplary
その典型性または模範的
become a
になる
The kind of consumption I just mentioned in the speech
先ほど講演で述べたような消費
consumption of spectacle
眼鏡の消費
That part is for
その部分は、
As for how the refugees themselves are subject to the image of these refugees
難民自身が難民のイメージにどのように影響されるのかについては、
critique and analysis
批評と分析
That is to say, many refugees may feel that they are being forced into a
つまり、多くの難民は、自分たちが強制されていると感じているのかもしれない。
or should i say
それとも言うべきか
be compelled or said to be expected to perform a
～を実行することを強制される、または期待されると言われる
good refugee such an image
良い難民、そのようなイメージ
This also contains some brave qualities
これには勇敢な資質も含まれています
contains some gentle qualities
いくつかの優しい性質を含んでいます
Contains some of these traits of tolerance to trauma
トラウマに対する耐性に関するこれらの特性のいくつかが含まれています
But not every refugee can fully present such a trait
しかし、すべての難民がそのような特性を完全に示すことができるわけではありません
But we will in these existing stories
しかし、私たちはこれらの既存の物語の中でそうします
To understand or recognize and construct a basic concept for refugees
難民に対する基本的な概念を理解し、認識し、構築する
thoughts and status
想いと現状
So this imaginary or constructed image
つまり、この想像上の、または構築されたイメージは
with the actual
実際の
Is there a kind of experience
一種の経験はありますか
Consideration
考慮
You have to meet this thing before I can accept you
私があなたを受け入れる前に、あなたはこれに会わなければなりません
Or will he form an oppressive relationship?
それとも抑圧的な関係を築くのでしょうか？
Because it's like this, I can't match it
こうだから似合わないよ
how i have to
どのようにしなければならないのか
Then this is what I want in this research
それから、これがこの研究で私が望んでいることです
trying to
しようとしています
just one of the opening
オープニングのひとつだけ
OK
OK
That is to say, we are often
つまり、私たちはしばしば
Often in the narrative, it actually regulates our
多くの場合、物語の中で、それは実際に私たちを規制します。
Acceptable and understandable range
許容範囲、理解できる範囲
OK
OK
The other one actually returns
もう一方は実際に戻ってきます
the food problem
食糧問題
Of course I have no actual food experience so it's hard to get in
もちろん実食経験がないので入りにくい
food above
上の食べ物
make a nice response
素敵な返事をする
But what I can probably say is that
しかし、おそらく言えることは、
to Ukraine
ウクライナへ
Take Ukraine as an example
ウクライナを例に挙げてみましょう
western fast
西部の速い
Receiving Ukrainian refugees with open arms
両手を広げてウクライナ難民を受け入れる
But from 2013 to 15 years
しかし、2013年から15年間
The Syrian Refugee Crisis
シリア難民危機
Up to now, virtual nanometer has still become a
現在に至るまで、仮想ナノメートルはまだ
Issues not adequately addressed within Europe
欧州内で十分に対処されていない問題
How to explain the difference here
ここでの違いをどう説明するか
Or how to make the difference here
または、ここで違いを生む方法
Let's see what exactly causes these differences
これらの違いの正確な原因を見てみましょう
Then this is probably facing reality
そうすると、これは現実に直面しているのかもしれない
one may not be a good answer
良い答えではないかもしれません
But that is to say, if we face the reality with courage
でもそれは、勇気を持って現実と向き合えば、
I think the critical thinking provided in the research
研究で得られた批判的思考は、
In fact, it may not be impossible to put it in a real field to test
実際、実際のフィールドに入れてテストすることは不可能ではないかもしれません
Maybe we might be talking too much about these thoughts
たぶん私たちはこれらの考えについて話しすぎているかもしれません
Then reality can slap us in the face and tell us that's not the case
そうすれば、現実は私たちの顔を平手打ちし、そうではないと告げるかもしれません
Then we'd love to take a reality check, too.
それから、私たちも現実の確認をしたいと思います。
But it is also possible that such a presupposition or imagination
しかし、そのような思い込みや想像が当てはまっている可能性もあります。
It is possible that in this real experience
おそらくこの実体験では、
help us see something different
何か違うものを見るのを手伝ってください
Of course we are also very happy
もちろん私たちもとても嬉しいです
In this sense, I think it is actually necessary
そういう意味では本当に必要だと思います
The academia and the food industry have more cooperation and expectations
学界と食品業界のさらなる協力と期待
In the past, we worked on the issue of migrant workers
私たちは過去に移民労働者の問題に取り組みました
In fact, there are many cooperations in the food industry
実際、食品業界では多くの協力関係があります
But in Naiming because of his international nature
しかし、彼の国際的な性質のためにナイミンでは
Relationships are also less accessible
人間関係も近づきにくくなる
This may require more efforts from us
これには私たちによるさらなる努力が必要になる可能性があります
thank you very much for your question
ご質問いただきありがとうございます
You are the gentleman in front of this society
あなたはこの社会の前の紳士です
our last three questions
最後の 3 つの質問
The first one
最初の1つ
hello i'm a biology student
こんにちは、私は生物学の学生です
So I guess the first thing we think
それで私たちが最初に考えるのは
We are all struggling for survival
私たちは皆、生き残るために苦労しています
all creatures are the same
すべての生き物は同じです
And the second thing that always comes to my mind is
そしていつも私の頭に浮かぶ2番目のことは、
franklin once said
フランクリンはかつてこう言った
That is, if you are unwilling to pay any obligation for freedom
つまり、自由のためにいかなる義務も支払うつもりがない場合、
this man does not deserve to be free
この男には自由になる資格はない
then my question
それから私の質問
Once when I was arguing with someone
あるとき、誰かと口論していたとき、
I say that maybe it's offensive to some people
人によっては気分を害するかもしれないと言いました
But I think Ms. Nongyuntai also said
でもノンユンタイさんも言ってたと思います
Dajiang Dahai is a refugee
ダジャン・ダハイさんは難民です
I said it was just refugees with guns
銃を持ったただの難民だと言いました
He told me that if you wear a gun, you are not a refugee.
彼は私に、銃を身に着けていれば難民ではない、と言いました。
I want to ask the teacher
先生に聞きたいのですが
if i give up defending myself today
もし私が今日自分を守ることを諦めたら
to be a refugee
難民になる
or am i a refugee today
それとも今日私は難民ですか？
But I'm willing to pick up a gun and defend myself
でも私は銃を手に取って自分を守るつもりです
I can get out of refugee status
難民状態から抜け出せる
good question
良い質問
Looks like the gift from today's seminar is pretty good
今日のセミナーのプレゼントはなかなかいいもののようです
So everyone's questions are very enthusiastic.
そのため、皆さんの質問はとても熱心です。
let me put it this way
このように言わせてください
If we go back to the previous UN-related definitions
以前の国連関連の定義に戻ると
Refugees have nothing to do with having a gun or not
難民は銃を持っているかどうかとは何の関係もありません
But that doesn't mean it doesn't matter that the refugees who are asking for trouble won't matter.
しかしだからといって、迷惑を求めてくる難民はどうでもいいというわけではない。
or a knife
またはナイフ
Right
右
creatures need to survive
生き物は生き残る必要がある
The creature will find his way out
生き物は出口を見つけるだろう
This is what I think everyone can agree with and accept.
これは誰もが同意し、受け入れることができると思います。
But to what extent do creatures
しかし、生物学的効果はどの程度まであるのか
to save his life
彼の命を救うために
or expand his livelihood
あるいは生計を拡大する
I think there is an ethical issue here
ここには倫理的な問題があると思う
OK that
わかりました
We generally think of refugees as victims, right?
私たちは一般的に難民を被害者だと考えていますよね？
Right
右
But Erlan told us
しかし、エルランは私たちに言いました
How to escape the image of the victim
被害者のイメージから逃れる方法
Make yourself famous first
まずは自分を有名にする
how to become famous
有名になる方法
you are going to steal
あなたは盗むつもりです
It's good to go to the robber
強盗に行くのは良いことだ
it doesn't matter
それは問題ではありません
as long as i can
私ができる限り
was seen
見られた
my voice can be heard
私の声が聞こえる
I can how
どうやってもできるよ
will be able to
ことができるようになります
have this condition to discuss my rights
私の権利について話し合うにはこの条件が必要です
that's where i want to go
そこが私が行きたい場所です
Consider that
それを考慮してください
Is there an ethic in being a refugee?
難民であることに倫理はありますか?
That sounds weird too, doesn't it?
それも奇妙に聞こえますよね？
you already
あなたはすでに
You are already a refugee, what ethics are you talking about?
あなたはすでに難民ですが、どのような倫理について話しているのですか？
but this is not
しかし、これはそうではありません
Do you mean being a refugee?
難民になるということですか？
no more ethics?
もう倫理は無いのか？
It's weird not to say the other way around, isn't it?
逆に言わないのは変ですよね？
So
それで
So I think your question
それであなたの質問は
Of course, there is a very realistic context and context in Taiwan.
もちろん、台湾には非常に現実的な背景と文脈があります。
this part i
この部分は私
I
私
Let me put it this way, let me not touch him so directly
こう言っておきますが、彼に直接触れないでください
But I come and go in the opposite direction
でも反対方向に行ったり来たり
The way to discuss this would probably be to say
この問題を議論する方法はおそらく次のように言うでしょう。
Um
えーっと
when we have
私たちが持っているとき
Enter
入力
When in a situation where you might become a refugee
難民になるかもしれない状況に陥ったとき
Well
良い
Whether to hold a gun or not may already be another question.
銃を持つか持たないかは、すでに別の問題かもしれない。
Come
来て
what we hope is
私たちが望んでいることは
such an experience
そのような経験
Don't happen to us though it sounds selfish
わがままに聞こえるかもしれませんが、私たちには起こらないでください
as if someone else
まるで別人のように
It doesn't matter if you're a refugee, but we don't want
あなたが難民かどうかは関係ありませんが、私たちはそれを望んでいません
but instead of saying
でも言う代わりに
When we can not go through this situation
この状況を乗り越えられないとき
or when we hope not to go through such a journey
あるいはそのような旅は経験したくないと願うとき
what should we do now
何をするべきだろう
then i think
それから私は思います
So this has nothing to do with holding a gun
つまり銃の所持とは関係ない
not completely irrelevant
完全に無関係ではない
But not so directly a cozorelation
しかし、それほど直接的なコゾ関係ではありません
With a gun, of course, you can kill a bloody road, right?
もちろん銃があれば、血まみれの道を殺すことができますよね？
barely say so
かろうじてそう言う
But what kind of road will the bloody road be?
しかし、その血塗られた道はどのような道になるのでしょうか？
Is it the way to live
それが生き方なのか
This is also what I think many of the refugee stories provide us with a
これは、難民の物語の多くが私たちに与えてくれるものでもあると思います。
Very different or bloody inspirations and experiences
非常に異なる、または血まみれのインスピレーションや経験
So I think I'll answer this question for now
ということで、今回はこの質問に答えてみようと思います
hope you are satisfied
あなたが満足していることを願っています
If you are not satisfied, we can discuss it in private.
ご満足いただけない場合は、個別にご相談させていただきます。
ok thanks
わかりました、ありがとう
The last two questions this classmate
最後の 2 つの質問はこのクラスメートです
The classmate in white clothes
白い服を着たクラスメイト
Hello, teacher. I am the candidate for the blood test.
こんにちは、先生、私は血液検査の候補者です。
then want to ask
それから聞きたいです
There have been extreme terrorist attacks in Europe in recent years
近年ヨーロッパでは過激なテロ攻撃が発生している
It's all about refugees
それはすべて難民に関するものです
Let me tell you the truth, if it happened in Taiwan
もしそれが台湾で起こったのなら、真実を話させてください
Personally, I'd be terrified of refugees
個人的には難民が怖い
So what kind of mentality should we have in order to trust the refugee group?
では、難民団体を信頼するにはどのような心構えを持てばよいのでしょうか。
And let's get this stereotype out of our minds
そして、この固定観念を頭から追い出しましょう
because the fact is that it happened
それが起こったのは事実だから
Mr. Xie
謝さん
This problem is mainly a hero out of a teenager
この問題は主に10代の若者のヒーローです
So the tough question comes from the youngest questioner
難しい質問は最年少の質問者からです
this stuff is really hard
これは本当に難しいです
I think this is of course also challenging our bottom line as human beings, right?
もちろん、これは私たち人間としての最終的な利益にも挑戦していると思いますよね？
That is, assuming your freshman experience was such an encounter
つまり、あなたの新入生の経験がそのような出会いだったと仮定すると、
And it is a clear relationship
そしてそれは明らかな関係です
For example, tell me something about me
たとえば、私について何か教えてください
It's because of this that he was sacrificed or injured.
そのために犠牲になったり、怪我をしたりしたのです。
Of course, that is a very clear signal to you, right?
もちろん、それはあなたにとって非常に明確なシグナルですよね？
then you'd like to say that you can keep those dangers or fears out of the equation
そうすれば、そのような危険や恐怖を考慮に入れることができると言いたいのでしょう。
that but i think on the one hand
それは一方で私は思います
Is that so?
そうですか？
If the history you just told is true
あなたが今話した歴史が本当なら
I can't remember now
今は思い出せない
is it true
それは本当ですか
but suppose you
しかし、あなたは
just say
言うだけ
i believe what you say is true
私はあなたの言うことが真実だと信じています
Then I can probably just say
それから私はおそらくただ言うことができます
Not every refugee is a terrorist
すべての難民がテロリストであるわけではない
Another one is to say
もう一つはこう言うことです
What is the context of these things?
これらの背景は何ですか?
How do we understand that these things happened
このようなことが起こったことをどのように理解すればよいでしょうか
not just focus or focus on
ただ焦点を当てたり集中したりするだけではなく
those who caused these events
これらの出来事を引き起こした人たち
identity of the author
著者の身元
because these identities are probably the easiest to identify
これらの ID はおそらく最も簡単に識別できるため、
easiest to see
一番見やすい
easiest to pick out
選び出すのが最も簡単
as different from us
私たちとは違うように
that part
その部分
to be noticed
注目される
But perhaps more importantly
しかし、おそらくもっと重要なことは、
what caused
何が原因だったのか
This specific identity and group
この特定のアイデンティティとグループ
to carry out such a
そのようなことを実行するために
The tragedy we don't want to see
見たくない悲劇
then this may be
それならこれかもしれない
I feel that in all encounters
あらゆる出会いでそう感じます
when tragic events
悲劇的な出来事があったとき
We should all actually think about it
みんなで実際に考えてみるべきだ
But at 911
しかし911では
In fact, there was a big
実は大きな出来事がありました
Reflection Except within the United States
米国内を除く反映
Everyone is very anti-terrorism outside
外では誰もがテロ反対に熱心だ
More often people think of
もっと頻繁に人々が考えるのは、
Why did these people suddenly come to America
なぜこの人たちは突然アメリカに来たのか
What the United States is doing in the Middle East
アメリカは中東で何をしているのか
make these so-called terrorists
これらをいわゆるテロリストにする
All were able to enter the United States through the US security check.
全員が米国のセキュリティチェックを通過して米国に入国できた。
even acquired these resources and capabilities for military operations
軍事作戦のためにこれらの資源と能力も獲得しました
I think it's something else
それは別のものだと思います
The direction we should ask and pursue
私たちが問い、目指すべき方向
thanks then our last question
ありがとう、それでは最後の質問です
Mr. Society, wear a mask, Mr. Society
ミスター・ソサエティ、マスクを着用してください、ミスター・ソサエティ
Hello teacher, thank you very much for your speech today
こんにちは、先生、今日はご講演ありがとうございました
Brilliant and then I have a question
すばらしいですね、それでは質問があります
It just happened to be in my heart for a while
それはたまたま私の心の中にしばらくあっただけです
Then just because of the princess, a friend of mine went
それから、プリンセスのためだけに、私の友人が行きました
He is a reporter from Taiwan
彼は台湾から来た記者です
Then he himself became very interested in refugee issues
その後、彼自身も難民問題に非常に興味を持つようになりました。
So he spent a lot of time in these years
それで彼はこの数年間に多くの時間を費やした
Find ways to interview and research countries around the world
世界中の国にインタビューして調査する方法を見つける
That includes Syria, Ukraine
その中にはシリアやウクライナも含まれる
Then there is the African country Afghanistan and so on
それからアフリカの国アフガニスタンなどです。
Then there are South American
あとは南米系
Then
それから
And because I'm friends with him
そして私は彼と友達なので
so i have seen him write something
それで私は彼が何かを書いているのを見たことがあります
Of course there are some things that we can understand
もちろん理解できる部分もある
Then there are many things that just echo the teacher's question
それから、先生の質問をそのまま反映するものがたくさんあります
In fact, the issue he wanted to discuss happened to be a lecture with the teacher today.
実は、彼が話したいと思っていた問題は、たまたま今日の先生との講義だった。
The theme is like
テーマはこんな感じ
Refugees aren't just one or two stereotypes actually
難民は実際には 1 つや 2 つの固定概念ではありません
It's not that he actually has various faces
実は色々な顔を持っているわけではない
These appearances are all in the mainstream media or
これらの出演はすべて主流メディアに掲載されるか、
interests outside political ideology
政治的イデオロギー以外の興味
Then his writing is the multi-headed appearance he wants to present.
そして彼の文章は彼が提示したい多頭身の姿である。
But I am particularly fond of the two characters in his record
しかし、私は彼のレコードの二人のキャラクターが特に好きです
speech to
に話す
special interest is
特別な興味は
What surprises me about these two is that they say they are refugees but they are true to themselves
この二人について私が驚いたのは、彼らは自分たちは難民だと言いながら、自分たちに正直であるということです。
Dare to fight for rights or what he deserves
権利や自分に値するもののためにあえて戦う
That one is like you just mentioned
それはあなたが今言ったようなものです
One of them is a Syrian refugee
そのうちの1人はシリア難民です
He saw the Ukrainian name in Europe
彼はヨーロッパでウクライナの名前を目にした
When you are taken care of relatively warmly
比較的温かく見守ってもらえると
when accepting
受け入れるとき
he is very angry
彼はとても怒っています
He said why the same European country
なぜ同じヨーロッパの国なのかと彼は言った
Much better for Ukraine than us
ウクライナにとっては我々よりずっと良い
He was very angry for asking
彼は尋ねたことでとても怒った
of course no answer
もちろん答えはありません
But it's surprising to me that it says
しかし、私にとって、そう言われるのは驚きです
Of course it's also the other way around
もちろんその逆もあるよ
Forcing myself to challenge my own cognition
自分自身の認識に挑戦することを自分に強いる
I just wanted to say what's so weird about it
何がそんなに変なのか言いたかっただけです
they are european countries
彼らはヨーロッパの国です
There is also a Christian civilization
キリスト教文明もある
same white complexion
同じ白い肌
then to
それから
But he doesn't think that's a reason
しかし彼はそれが理由だとは思っていない
He angrily questioned
彼は怒って質問した
And then another example is a guy from Neglia
そして別の例はネリア出身の男性です
He is actually strictly speaking
彼は実際には厳密に言ってます
not your typical refugee
典型的な難民ではない
He is going to study in England
彼はイギリスに留学するつもりです
But since then it happened to him that he had a disease
しかしそれ以来、彼は病気を患っていることが判明しました
that disease if he goes back to negilia
彼がネギリアに戻ったらその病気
There is no way to get proper care
適切なケアを受ける方法がない
because his brother died
彼の兄が亡くなったので
So there seems to be a law in the UK that says
イギリスには次のような法律があるようです
You can stay in the UK for medical reasons
医療上の理由でイギリスに滞在できる
but
しかし
However, due to various technical problems
しかし、さまざまな技術的な問題により、
He was not accepted by the British government
彼は英国政府に受け入れられなかった
So he went to court with the British government for many years
そこで彼は長年にわたってイギリス政府と法廷に立った
Then in this interview he said
そしてこのインタビューで彼はこう言いました
He complained that he thought the British government had not properly
彼は英国政府が適切に対応していないのではないかと不満を述べた。
give him his due rights
彼に当然の権利を与える
So he angrily criticized the British government
そこで彼は英国政府を怒って批判した
And he also has the support of a lot of Britons
そして彼は多くの英国人からも支持されています
I feel that the British government is not doing a good job.
イギリス政府は良い仕事をしていないように感じます。
should give him the right
彼に権利を与えるべきだ
Caused him to pretend to be a youth to go to court
彼に若者のふりをさせて法廷に行かせた
Normal life and due development are thus on the wheel
こうして通常の生活と当然の発展が軌道に乗る
Then I got curious and said
それから私は興味を持ってこう言いました
Why is this guy not actually a British citizen?
なぜこの男は実際にはイギリス国民ではないのでしょうか？
Not a citizen of Ukraine or any other country
ウクライナまたは他の国の国民ではない
But he thinks he can have
しかし彼はそれができると考えている
great right to demand even he can criticize
彼が批判できるとしても要求する大きな権利
Then also got a case like the British
その後、イギリスのような事件も起きた
He is also supported by British citizens
彼は英国国民からも支持されている
Seems like the Guardian also reported his case.
ガーディアン紙も彼の事件を報道したようだ。
I'm just curious, why?
ただ興味があるのですが、なぜですか？
These refugees feel that they have
これらの難民は次のように感じています。
That power and right
その力と権利
Then another reason is
それから、もう一つの理由は、
Another question is that
もう一つの質問は、
Is it true that European countries have developed a
ヨーロッパ諸国が開発したというのは本当ですか?
A new discourse looks at the matter of citizenship
市民権の問題を考察する新たな議論
so that as you just discussed is to say
つまり、あなたが今議論したように、
like A'olan would criticize
アオランが批判するように
If you don't have citizenship you don't have human rights
市民権がなければ人権もない
that sovereignty
その主権
Should human rights and sovereignty be tied together?
人権と主権は結び付けられるべきでしょうか?
Or in fact, European countries can do better
あるいは実際、ヨーロッパ諸国はもっとうまくやれるはずだ
Then you mentioned a little bit
それからあなたは少し言及しました
The latest discussion of that in Europe
ヨーロッパにおけるそれに関する最新の議論
But can the teacher be there more?
でも、先生はもっとそこにいられるでしょうか？
Let’s talk a little more about the past few years in Europe
ヨーロッパの過去数年間についてもう少し詳しく話しましょう
Discussion on the relationship between human rights and refugees
人権と難民の関係についてのディスカッション
Is there some new development like this?
こういった新たな展開はあるのでしょうか？
Thanks
ありがとう
OK, I will simply add something like this
わかりました。次のようなものを追加します
the first is
一つ目は
The refugee problem is in Europe as in America as in Asia
難民問題はヨーロッパでもアメリカでもアジアでもある
is a very different configuration
非常に異なる構成です
OK
OK
Well, in Europe I think there is a special place
そうですね、ヨーロッパには特別な場所があると思います
because it is the eu
EUだから
So when refugees come in
だから、難民が入ってくると、
It really only needs to be accepted
本当に受け入れるしかない
it may be conditioned to be able to move
動けるようになることが条件になっているのかもしれない
Or he may also choose to speak to him
あるいは、彼は彼と話すことを選ぶかもしれません
Conditions will be better to move
移動するには条件が良くなります
OK, then this is what I want in the real thing
OK、これが私が実際に欲しいものです
Some examples we can see
私たちが見ることができるいくつかの例
that means he's here
それは彼がここにいるということです
For example, he crossed the Mediterranean from Syria
たとえば、彼はシリアから地中海を渡った。
came to greece
ギリシャに来ました
In fact, it is because Greece is relatively easy to get to.
実際、ギリシャは比較的行きやすいからです。
in many senses
いろんな意味で
And it's a route that's been traveled many times
そして何度も通った道です
So here we can actually see
ここで実際に見ることができます
Refugees have some knowledge accumulation
難民にはある程度の知識の蓄積がある
Is he has long the path of this refugee
それは、この難民にとって彼には長い道のりがあるということです
Formed a whole set of this process
このプロセス全体を形成
if we may say so
そう言えば
Then this process includes our selection
このプロセスには私たちの選択が含まれます
It's where the refugees choose to settle.
そこは難民たちが定住することを選んだ場所だ。
where to move
どこに移動するか
and where to get the identity
そしてアイデンティティをどこで入手するか
some different options like this
このようないくつかの異なるオプション
including this one we were just talking about about North Korea
先ほど北朝鮮について話したこれも含めて
When this experience of North Korean defectors
脱北者のこの経験があったとき、
In fact, many North Korean defectors, of course
もちろん、実際には多くの脱北者がいる。
I want to go to South Korea
韓国に行きたいです
Then he opened his hands at the beginning
それから彼は最初に手を広げた
hug these defectors
これらの脱北者たちを抱きしめてください
Because this can prove that South Korea is
これは韓国がそうだということを証明できるからだ。
It is the most reasonable and legal representative of the two Korean governments, right?
韓国両国政府の最も合理的で法的な代表者ですよね？
This is very exhausting for the relationship between the two Koreas.
これは南北関係にとって非常に疲弊するものだ。
But because too many people came
でも人が多すぎたので
So the governments of the two Koreas feel that this will create another kind of fear and crisis
したがって、南北両国政府は、これが別の種類の恐怖と危機を引き起こすと感じている
So he started shutting down the flow of North Korean defectors into South Korea.
そこで彼は、韓国への脱北者の流入を遮断し始めた。
This made it impossible for these North Korean defectors to leave smoothly.
このため、脱北者たちはスムーズな出国が不可能となった。
From Taiwan to North Korea to China and then to South Korea
台湾から北朝鮮、中国、そして韓国へ
So he started moving elsewhere
それで彼は別の場所に引っ越し始めました
So what I'm going to say is to go back to your question
それで私が言いたいのはあなたの質問に戻ります
A very core place in it is
その中の非常に核となる場所は、
Refugees are not people without knowledge
難民は知識のない人ではありません
This is the first one I think we should be very aware of
これは私たちがよく認識する必要があると思う最初のことです
That is, refugees are not only people without knowledge
つまり、難民は知識を持たない人だけではないということです。
And they probably have a whole lot of knowledge about fleeing
そして彼らはおそらく逃亡についての知識を豊富に持っているでしょう
we don't have
私たちにはありません
So when I read topics related to refugee studies
ですから、難民研究に関連するトピックを読むと、
I was surprised that when many refugees fled
多くの難民が逃げてきたときは驚きました
is wearing a mobile phone
携帯電話を着けている
Then there are cell phones so you have GPS
携帯電話もあるのでGPSもある
then where can how how how how how how
では、どこで、どのように、どのように、どのように、どのようにして
then this is
それならこれは
The thing we didn't think about when we wanted refugees before
以前難民を望んでいたときには考えもしなかったこと
So I think the part about keeping pace with the times
ですから、時代に遅れないようにするという部分は重要だと思います
Actually in Europe
実はヨーロッパでは
The first one, of course, is that the understanding of refugees keeps pace with the times.
もちろん、第一の理由は、難民に対する理解が時代に合わせて進んでいることです。
In addition, in Europe because of such a state
また、ヨーロッパではこのような状態のため、
So Europe is constantly
したがって、ヨーロッパは常に
The more progressive person
より進歩的な人ほど
What is actually being discussed is
実際に議論されているのは、
How do we carry out a so-called all-European management
いわゆるオールヨーロッパ経営をどのように行うか
Don't let all the refugees go through it, let's say italy
すべての難民を通過させないでください、たとえばイタリアにしましょう
or among them in greece
あるいはギリシャの彼らの間で
can share
共有できる
Shared among EU countries
EU諸国間で共有
Form a mechanism to enable these people to have a suitable placement
そうした人材が適切に配置される仕組みを構築する
I understand that this is still under discussion
これはまだ議論中であることを理解しています
Such a proposition actually encountered a lot of backlash.
このような提案は実際に多くの反発に遭いました。
Maybe Germany is comparatively speaking
おそらくドイツは比較的そう言えます
Welcome is a country that is more willing to tolerate and accept
もっと寛容で受け入れる国を歓迎します
But some other countries may not be so willing, like Italy
しかし、イタリアのように他の国はそれほど積極的ではないかもしれない
so here maybe
だからここで多分
Probably have to go back to the whole EU
おそらくEU全体に戻らなければならないだろう
Some special situations in each country
各国の特殊な状況
come to understand these
これらを理解するようになる
Individual country situation relative to refugee movements
難民の動きに関する各国の状況
I think this is probably what I can provide
たぶんこれが私が提供できるものだと思います
Simply add like this
このように追加するだけです
thanks for your question
ご質問ありがとうございます
well thank you very much for this tonight
さて、今夜は本当にありがとうございました
Professor Wang gave us a wonderful speech
王教授が素晴らしいスピーチをしてくれました
offers us much to reflect on
私たちに多くの反省点を与えてくれる
So let's applaud him now
だから今は彼に拍手を送りましょう
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you very much for your participation
ご参加いただき誠にありがとうございました